<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../sherlock_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<passage number="11">
        <title>XI. THE ADVENTURE OF THE BERYL CORONET</title>
        <story>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson"><char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes"
                                        >Holmes</char>,</quote> said I as <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> stood one morning in our
                        bow-window looking down the street</action>, <quote speaker="johnWatson">here is a
                                madman coming along. It seems rather sad that his relatives should
                                allow him to come out alone.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">My friend</char> rose lazily from his armchair and stood with his hands in the pockets
                        of his dressing-gown, looking over my shoulder</action>. It was a bright, crisp
                        February morning, and the snow of the day before still lay deep upon the
                        ground, shimmering brightly in the wintry sun. Down the centre of Baker
                        Street it had been ploughed into a brown crumbly band by the traffic, but at
                        either side and on the heaped-up edges of the footpaths it still lay as
                        white as when it fell. The grey pavement had been cleaned and scraped, but
                        was still dangerously slippery, so that there were fewer passengers than
                        usual. Indeed, from the direction of the Metropolitan Station no one was
                        coming save the single gentleman whose eccentric conduct had drawn my
                        attention.</p>
                <p>He was a man of about fifty, tall, portly, and imposing, with a massive, strongly
                        marked face and a commanding figure. He was dressed in a sombre yet rich
                        style, in black frock-coat, shining hat, neat brown gaiters, and well-cut
                        pearl-grey trousers. Yet his actions were in absurd contrast to the dignity
                        of his dress and features, for he was running hard, with occasional little
                        springs, such as a weary man gives who is little accustomed to set any tax
                        upon his legs. <action>As <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> ran he jerked his hands up and down, waggled his head,
                        and writhed his face into the most extraordinary contortions.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">What on earth can be the matter with him?</quote> I
                        asked. <quote speaker="johnWatson"><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">He</char> is looking up at the numbers of the
                                houses.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I believe that he is coming here,</quote> said
                                        <action><char gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, rubbing his
                                hands</action>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Here?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Yes; I rather think he is coming to consult me
                                professionally. I think that I recognise the symptoms. Ha! did I not
                                tell you?</quote> <action>As <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> spoke, the man, puffing and blowing, rushed
                        at our door and pulled at our bell until the whole house resounded with the
                        clanging.</action></p>
                <p>A few moments later <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> was in our room, still puffing, still gesticulating</action>, but
                        with so fixed a look of grief and despair in his eyes that our smiles were
                        turned in an instant to horror and pity. For a while <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> could not get his
                        words out, but swayed his body and plucked at his hair like one who has been
                        driven to the extreme limits of his reason</action>. Then, <action>suddenly springing to his
                                feet, <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> beat his head against the wall with such force</action> that <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson, sherlockHolmes">we both</char> rushed
                        upon him and tore him away to the centre of the room</action>. Sherlock <action><char
                                        gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> pushed him down into the
                                easy-chair and, sitting beside him, patted his hand and chatted with
                                him in the easy, soothing tones which he knew so well how to
                                employ</action>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You have come to me to tell your story, have you
                                not?</quote> said he. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You are
                                fatigued with your haste. Pray wait until you have recovered
                                yourself, and then I shall be most happy to look into any little
                                problem which you may submit to me.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">The man</char> sat for a minute or more with a heaving chest, fighting against his
                        emotion. Then he passed his handkerchief over his brow, set his lips tight,
                        and turned his face towards us.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">No doubt you think me mad?</quote> said he.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I see that you have had some great
                                trouble,</quote> responded <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes"
                                >Holmes</char>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">God knows I have!—a trouble which is enough to
                                unseat my reason, so sudden and so terrible is it. Public disgrace I
                                might have faced, although I am a man whose character has never yet
                                borne a stain. Private affliction also is the lot of every man; but
                                the two coming together, and in so frightful a form, have been
                                enough to shake my very soul. Besides, it is not I alone. The very
                                noblest in the land may suffer unless some way be found out of this
                                horrible affair.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Pray compose yourself, sir,</quote> said <char
                                gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">and let
                                me have a clear account of who you are and what it is that has
                                befallen you.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">My name,</quote> answered our visitor, <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">is probably familiar to your ears. I am
                                        <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Alexander Holder</char>, of the banking
                                firm of Holder &amp; Stevenson, of Threadneedle Street.</quote></p>
                <p>The name was indeed well known to us as belonging to the senior partner in the
                        second largest private banking concern in the City of London. What could
                        have happened, then, to bring one of the foremost citizens of London to this
                        most pitiable pass? <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes, johnWatson">We</char> waited, all curiosity</action>, until with another effort he
                        braced himself to tell his story.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I feel that time is of value,</quote> said he;
                                <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">that is why I hastened here when
                                the police inspector suggested that I should secure your
                                co-operation. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> came to Baker Street by the Underground and hurried
                                from there on foot</action>, for the cabs go slowly through this snow. That
                                is why I was so out of breath, for I am a man who takes very little
                                exercise. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> feel better now, and I will put the facts before you as
                                shortly and yet as clearly as I can</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">It is, of course, well known to you that in a
                                successful banking business as much depends upon our being able to
                                find remunerative investments for our funds as upon our increasing
                                our connection and the number of our depositors. One of our most
                                lucrative means of laying out money is in the shape of loans, where
                                the security is unimpeachable. We have done a good deal in this
                                direction during the last few years, and there are many noble
                                families to whom we have advanced large sums upon the security of
                                their pictures, libraries, or plate.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Yesterday morning <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> was seated in my office at
                                the bank when a card was brought in to me by one of the clerks. </action>I
                                started when I saw the name, for it was that of none other
                                than—well, perhaps even to you I had better say no more than that it
                                was a name which is a household word all over the earth—one of the
                                highest, noblest, most exalted names in England. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> was overwhelmed
                                        by the honour and attempted, when he entered</action>, to say so, but <action><char gender = "male" name = "Clerk">he</char>
                                plunged at once into business with the air of a man who wishes to
                                hurry quickly through a disagreeable task.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk"><char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr.
                                                Holder</char>,</subq> said he, <subq speaker="u_Clerk"
                                        >I have been informed that you are in the habit of advancing
                                        money.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">The firm does so
                                        when the security is good.</subq> I answered.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">It is absolutely essential
                                        to me,</subq> said he, <subq speaker="u_Clerk">that I should
                                        have £ 50,000 at once. I could, of course, borrow so
                                        trifling a sum ten times over from my friends, but I much
                                        prefer to make it a matter of business and to carry out that
                                        business myself. In my position you can readily understand
                                        that it is unwise to place one’s self under
                                        obligations.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">For how long,
                                        may I ask, do you want this sum?</subq> I asked.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">Next Monday I have a large
                                        sum due to me, and I shall then most certainly repay what
                                        you advance, with whatever interest you think it right to
                                        charge. But it is very essential to me that the money should
                                        be paid at once.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">I should be
                                        happy to advance it without further parley from my own
                                        private purse,</subq> said I, <subq
                                        speaker="alexanderHolder"> were it not that the strain would
                                        be rather more than it could bear. If, on the other hand, I
                                        am to do it in the name of the firm, then in justice to my
                                        partner I must insist that, even in your case, every
                                        businesslike precaution should be taken.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">I should much prefer to
                                        have it so,</subq> said he, raising up a square, black
                                morocco case which he had laid beside his chair. <subq
                                        speaker="u_Clerk">You have doubtless heard of the Beryl
                                        Coronet?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">One of the most
                                        precious public possessions of the empire,</subq> said
                                I.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">Precisely.</subq> <action><char gender = "male" name = "Clerk">He</char>
                                opened the case</action>, and there, imbedded in soft, flesh-coloured velvet,
                                lay the magnificent piece of jewellery which he had named. <subq
                                        speaker="u_Clerk">There are thirty-nine enormous
                                        beryls,</subq> said he, <subq speaker="u_Clerk">and the price
                                        of the gold chasing is incalculable. The lowest estimate
                                        would put the worth of the coronet at double the sum which I
                                        have asked. I am prepared to leave it with you as my
                                        security.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> took the precious case into my hands and
                                looked in some perplexity from it to my illustrious
                        client.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">You doubt its
                                        value?</subq> he asked.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">Not at all. I
                                        only doubt—</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">The propriety of my
                                        leaving it. You may set your mind at rest about that. I
                                        should not dream of doing so were it not absolutely certain
                                        that I should be able in four days to reclaim it. It is a
                                        pure matter of form. Is the security
                                sufficient?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder"
                                >Ample.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="u_Clerk">You understand, <char
                        gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>, that <action><char gender = "male" name = "Clerk">I</char> am giving
                                        you a strong proof of the confidence which I have in you</action>,
                                        founded upon all that I have heard of you. I rely upon you
                                        not only to be discreet and to refrain from all gossip upon
                                        the matter but, above all, to preserve this coronet with
                                        every possible precaution because I need not say that a
                                        great public scandal would be caused if any harm were to
                                        befall it. Any injury to it would be almost as serious as
                                        its complete loss, for there are no beryls in the world to
                                        match these, and it would be impossible to replace them. <action><char gender = "male" name = "Clerk">I</char>
                                        leave it with you, however, with every confidence, and I
                                        shall call for it in person on Monday
                                morning.</action></subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Seeing that my client was anxious to leave, I
                        said no more but, <action>calling for my cashier, <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> ordered him to pay over
                                fifty £ 1000 notes</action>. When I was alone once more, however, with the
                                precious case lying upon the table in front of me, I could not but
                                think with some misgivings of the immense responsibility which it
                                entailed upon me. There could be no doubt that, as it was a national
                                possession, a horrible scandal would ensue if any misfortune should
                                occur to it. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> already regretted having ever consented to take
                                        charge of it</action>. However, it was too late to alter the matter now, so <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char>
                                locked it up in my private safe and turned once more to my
                                work</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">When evening came I felt that it would be an
                                imprudence to leave so precious a thing in the office behind me.
                                Bankers’ safes had been forced before now, and why should not mine
                                be? If so, how terrible would be the position in which I should find
                                myself! <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> determined, therefore, that for the next few days I would
                                always carry the case backward and forward with me</action>, so that it might
                        never be really out of my reach. With this intention, <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> called a cab
                                and drove out to my house at Streatham, carrying the jewel with me.
                                I did not breathe freely until I had taken it upstairs and locked it
                                in the bureau of my dressing-room.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">And now a word as to my household, Mr. <char
                        gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, for <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> wish you to thoroughly
                                understand the situation</action>. My groom and my page sleep out of the
                                house, and may be set aside altogether. I have three maid-servants
                                who have been with me a number of years and whose absolute
                                reliability is quite above suspicion. Another, <char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">Lucy Parr</char>, the second
                        waiting-maid, has only been in my service a few months. <action><char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">She</char> came
                                with an excellent character</action>, however, and has always given me
                                satisfaction. She is a very pretty girl and has attracted admirers
                                who have occasionally hung about the place. That is the only
                                drawback which we have found to her, but we believe her to be a
                                thoroughly good girl in every way.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">So much for the servants. My family itself is so
                                small that it will not take me long to describe it. I am a widower
                                and have an only son, <char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">Arthur</char>. He has been
                                a disappointment to me, Mr. <char gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>—a
                                grievous disappointment. I have no doubt that I am myself to blame.
                                People tell me that <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> have spoiled him.</action> Very likely I have. When my
                        dear wife died <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> felt that he was all I had to love</action>. I could not
                        bear to see the smile fade even for a moment from his face. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> have
                                never denied him a wish</action>. Perhaps it would have been better for both
                                of us had I been sterner, but I meant it for the best.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">It was naturally my intention that he should
                                succeed me in my business, but he was not of a business turn. He was
                                wild, wayward, and, to speak the truth, I could not trust him in the
                                handling of large sums of money. When he was young <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char> became a
                                member of an aristocratic club</action>, and there, having charming manners,
                                he was soon the intimate of a number of men with long purses and
                                expensive habits. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> learned to play heavily at cards and to
                                squander money on the turf</action>, until he had again and again to come to
                                me and implore me to give him an advance upon his allowance, that he
                                might settle his debts of honour. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> tried more than once to break
                                away from the dangerous company</action> which he was keeping, but each time
                                the influence of his friend, Sir George <char gender="male"
                                        name="georgeBurnwell">Burnwell</char>, was enough to draw
                                him back again.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">And, indeed, I could not wonder that such a man
                                as Sir George <char gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell"
                                        >Burnwell</char> should gain an influence over him, for <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char>
                                                has frequently brought him to my house</action>, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> have found myself that
                                I could hardly resist the fascination of his manner</action>. He is older
                                than <char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">Arthur</char>, a man of the world to his
                                finger-tips, one who had been everywhere, seen everything, a
                                brilliant talker, and a man of great personal beauty. Yet when I
                                think of him in cold blood, far away from the glamour of his
                                presence, I am convinced from his cynical speech and the look which
                                I have caught in his eyes that he is one who should be deeply
                                distrusted. So I think, and so, too, thinks my little <char
                                        gender="female" name="maryHolder">Mary</char>, who has a
                                woman’s quick insight into character.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">And now there is only she to be described. She
                                is my niece; but when my brother died five years ago and left her
                                alone in the world <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> adopted her, and have looked upon her ever
                                since as my daughter</action>. She is a sunbeam in my house—sweet, loving,
                                beautiful, a wonderful manager and housekeeper, yet as tender and
                                quiet and gentle as a woman could be. She is my right hand. I do not
                                know what I could do without her. In only one matter has she ever
                                gone against my wishes. Twice my boy has asked her to marry him, for
                                he loves her devotedly, but each time she has refused him. I think
                                that if anyone could have drawn him into the right path it would
                                have been she, and that his marriage might have changed his whole
                                life; but now, alas! it is too late—forever too late!</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Now, Mr. <char gender="male"
                                        name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, you know the people who
                                live under my roof, and I shall continue with my miserable
                                story.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">When we were taking coffee in the drawing-room
                                that night after dinner, I told <char gender="male"
                                        name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> and <char
                                        gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Mary</char> my experience, and of the
                                precious treasure which we had under our roof, suppressing only the
                                name of my client. <action><char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">Lucy Parr</char>, who had brought in the coffee, had, I
                                am sure, left the room</action>; but I cannot swear that the door was closed.
                                        <char gender="female" name="maryHolder">Mary</char> and
                                        <char gender="male" name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> were
                                much interested and wished to see the famous coronet, but I thought
                                it better not to disturb it.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Where have you put
                                        it?</subq> asked <char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">
                        Arthur</char>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">In my own
                                        bureau.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Well, I hope to goodness
                                        the house won’t be burgled during the night.</subq> said
                                he.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">It is locked
                                        up,</subq> I answered.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Oh, any old key will fit
                                        that bureau. When I was a youngster I have opened it myself
                                        with the key of the box-room cupboard.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">He often had a wild way of talking, so that I
                        thought little of what he said. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> followed me to my room, however,
                                that night with a very grave face</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Look here, dad,</subq>
                                said he with his eyes cast down, <subq speaker="arthurHolder">can you let
                                        me have £ 200?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">No, I
                                        cannot!</subq> I answered sharply. <subq
                                        speaker="alexanderHolder">I have been far too generous with
                                        you in money matters.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">You have been very
                                        kind,</subq> said he, <subq speaker="arthurHolder">but I must have
                                        this money, or else I can never show my face inside the club
                                        again.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">And a very good
                                        thing, too!</subq> I cried.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Yes, but you would not
                                        have me leave it a dishonoured man,</subq> said he. <subq
                                        speaker="arthurHolder">I could not bear the disgrace. I must raise
                                        the money in some way, and if you will not let me have it,
                                        then I must try other means.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I was very angry, for this was the third demand
                                during the month. <subq speaker="alexanderHolder">You shall not have
                                        a farthing from me,</subq> I cried, on which <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char> bowed and
                                left the room without another word</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">When he was gone <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> unlocked my bureau, made sure
                        that my treasure was safe, and locked it again</action>. Then <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> started to go
                                round the house to see that all was secure—a duty</action> which I usually
                                leave to <char gender="female" name="maryHolder">Mary</char> but
                                which I thought it well to perform myself that night. As I came down
                                the stairs I saw <char gender="female" name="maryHolder"
                                        >Mary</char> herself at the side window of the hall, which
                        <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> closed and fastened as I approached</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="maryHolder">Tell me,
                                        dad,</subq> said she, looking, I thought, a little
                                disturbed, <subq speaker="maryHolder">did you give <char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">Lucy</char>, the maid,
                                        leave to go out to-night?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">Certainly
                                        not.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="maryHolder"><action><char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">She</char> came in just
                                        now by the back door</action>. I have no doubt that she has only been
                                        to the side gate to see someone, but I think that it is
                                        hardly safe and should be stopped.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">You must speak
                                        to her in the morning, or I will if you prefer it. Are you
                                        sure that everything is fastened?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="maryHolder">Quite sure,
                                        dad.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">Then,
                        good-night.</subq> <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> kissed her and went up to my bedroom
                                again</action>, where I was soon asleep.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I am endeavouring to tell you everything, Mr.
                                        <char gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, which may have any
                        bearing upon the case, but <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> beg that you will question me upon any
                                point which I do not make clear</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">On the contrary, your statement is singularly
                                lucid.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> come to a part of my story now in which I
                                should wish to be particularly so</action>. I am not a very heavy sleeper,
                                and the anxiety in my mind tended, no doubt, to make me even less so
                                than usual. About two in the morning, then, <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> was awakened by some
                                sound in the house</action>. It had ceased ere I was wide awake, but it had
                                left an impression behind it as though a window had gently closed
                                somewhere. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder"></char> lay listening with all my ears</action>. Suddenly, to my horror,
                                there was a distinct sound of footsteps moving softly in the next
                                room. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> slipped out of bed, all palpitating with fear, and peeped
                                round the corner of my dressing-room door</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder"><char
                                                gender="male" name="arthurHolder"
                                        >Arthur</char>!</subq> I screamed, <subq
                                        speaker="alexanderHolder">you villain! you thief! How dare
                                        you touch that coronet?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">The gas was half up, as I had left it, and my
                                unhappy boy, dressed only in his shirt and trousers, was standing
                                beside the light, holding the coronet in his hands. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> appeared to
                                be wrenching at it, or bending it with all his strength</action>. At my cry
                        <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> dropped it from his grasp and turned as pale as death</action>. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> snatched
                                it up and examined it</action>. One of the gold corners, with three of the
                                beryls in it, was missing.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">You
                                        blackguard!</subq> I shouted, beside myself with rage. <subq
                                        speaker="alexanderHolder">You have destroyed it! You have
                                        dishonoured me forever! Where are the jewels which you have
                                        stolen?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Stolen!</subq> he
                                cried.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">Yes,
                                        thief!</subq> I roared, shaking him by the
                        shoulder.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">There are none missing.
                                        There cannot be any missing,</subq> said he.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">There are three
                                        missing. And you know where they are. Must I call you a liar
                                        as well as a thief? Did I not see you trying to tear off
                                        another piece?</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">You have called me names
                                        enough,</subq> said he, <subq speaker="arthurHolder">I will not
                                        stand it any longer. I shall not say another word about this
                                        business, since you have chosen to insult me. I will leave
                                        your house in the morning and make my own way in the
                                        world.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">You shall leave
                                        it in the hands of the police!</subq> I cried half-mad with
                                grief and rage. <subq speaker="alexanderHolder">I shall have this
                                        matter probed to the bottom.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">You shall learn nothing
                                        from me,</subq> said he with a passion such as I should not
                                have thought was in his nature. <subq speaker="arthurHolder">If you choose
                                        to call the police, let the police find what they
                                        can.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">By this time the whole house was astir, for <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char>
                                had raised my voice in my anger</action>. <action><char gender="female"
                                                name="maryHolder">Mary</char> was the first to
                                        rush into my room</action>, and, at the sight of the coronet
                                and of <char gender="male" name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char>’s
                        face, <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> read the whole story and, with a scream, fell down
                                senseless on the ground</action>. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> sent the housemaid for the police and put
                                the investigation into their hands at once</action>. When the inspector and a
                                constable entered the house, <action><char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">
                                                Arthur</char>, who had stood sullenly with his arms
                                        folded, asked me whether it was my intention to charge him
                                        with theft</action>. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> answered that it had ceased to be a
                                private matter</action>, but had become a public one, since the ruined
                                coronet was national property. I was determined that the law should
                                have its way in everything.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">At least,</subq> said he,
                                        <subq speaker="arthurHolder">you will not have me arrested at
                                        once. It would be to your advantage as well as mine if I
                                        might leave the house for five minutes.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">That you may get
                                        away, or perhaps that you may conceal what you have
                                        stolen,</subq> said I. And then, realising the dreadful
                        position in which I was placed, <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> implored him to remember that not
                                only my honour but that of one who was far greater than I was at
                                stake</action>; and that he threatened to raise a scandal which would
                                convulse the nation. He might avert it all if he would but tell me
                                what he had done with the three missing stones.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="alexanderHolder">You may as well
                                        face the matter,</subq> said I; <subq
                                        speaker="alexanderHolder">you have been caught in the act,
                                        and no confession could make your guilt more heinous. If you
                                        but make such reparation as is in your power, by telling us
                                        where the beryls are, all shall be forgiven and
                                        forgotten.</subq></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="arthurHolder">Keep your forgiveness for
                        those who ask for it,</subq> <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char> answered, turning away from
                                me with a sneer</action>. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> saw that he was too hardened for any words of
                                        mine to influence him</action>. There was but one way for it. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> called in the
                                inspector and gave him into custody</action>. A search was made at once not
                                only of his person but of his room and of every portion of the house
                                where he could possibly have concealed the gems; but no trace of
                                them could be found, nor would the wretched boy open his mouth for
                                all our persuasions and our threats. This morning he was removed to
                                a cell, and I, after going through all the police formalities, have
                                hurried round to you to implore you to use your skill in unravelling
                                the matter. The police have openly confessed that they can at
                                present make nothing of it. You may go to any expense which you
                                think necessary. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> have already offered a reward of £ 1000</action>. My God,
                                what shall I do! I have lost my honour, my gems, and my son in one
                                night. Oh, what shall I do!</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">He</char> put a hand on either side of his head and rocked himself to and fro, droning
                        to himself like a child whose grief has got beyond words.</action></p>
                <p>Sherlock <action><char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> sat
                                silent for some few minutes, with his brows knitted and his eyes
                                fixed upon the fire</action>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do you receive much company?</quote> he
                        asked.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">None save my partner with his family and an
                                occasional friend of <char gender="male" name="arthurHolder"
                                        >Arthur</char>’s. Sir George <char gender="male" name = "georgeBurnwell">
                                        Burnwell</char> has been several times lately. No one else,
                                I think.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do you go out much in society?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><char gender="male" name="arthurHolder"
                                        >Arthur</char> does. <char gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Mary</char> and I
                                stay at home. We neither of us care for it.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">That is unusual in a young girl.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">She is of a quiet nature. Besides, she is not
                                so very young. She is four-and-twenty.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">This matter, from what you say, seems to have
                                been a shock to her also.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Terrible! She is even more affected than
                                I.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You have neither of you any doubt as to your
                                son’s guilt?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">How can we have when I saw him with my own eyes
                                with the coronet in his hands.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I hardly consider that a conclusive proof. Was
                                the remainder of the coronet at all injured?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Yes, it was twisted.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do you not think, then, that he might have been
                                trying to straighten it?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">God bless you! You are doing what you can for
                                him and for me. But it is too heavy a task. What was he doing there
                                at all? If his purpose were innocent, why did he not say
                        so?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Precisely. And if it were guilty, why did he not
                                invent a lie? His silence appears to me to cut both ways. There are
                                several singular points about the case. What did the police think of
                                the noise which awoke you from your sleep?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">They considered that it might be caused by
                                                <action><char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">Arthur</char>’s closing
                                        his bedroom door.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">A likely story! As if a man bent on felony would
                                slam his door so as to wake a household. What did they say, then, of
                                the disappearance of these gems?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">They are still sounding the planking and probing
                                the furniture in the hope of finding them.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Have they thought of looking outside the
                                house?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Yes, they have shown extraordinary energy. The
                                whole garden has already been minutely examined.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Now, my dear sir,</quote> said <char
                                gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote
                                speaker="sherlockHolmes">is it not obvious to you now that this
                                matter really strikes very much deeper than either you or the police
                                were at first inclined to think? It appeared to you to be a simple
                                case; to me it seems exceedingly complex. Consider what is involved
                                by your theory. You suppose that your son came down from his bed,
                                went, at great risk, to your dressing-room, opened your bureau, took
                                out your coronet, broke off by main force a small portion of it,
                                went off to some other place, concealed three gems out of the
                                thirty-nine, with such skill that nobody can find them, and then
                                returned with the other thirty-six into the room in which he exposed
                                himself to the greatest danger of being discovered. I ask you now,
                                is such a theory tenable?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">But what other is there?</quote> cried <char
                                gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">the banker</char> with a gesture of despair. <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">If his motives were innocent, why does he
                                not explain them?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is our task to find that out,</quote> replied
                                <char gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>; <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"
                                >so now, if you please, <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>, we
                                will set off for Streatham together, and devote an hour to glancing
                                a little more closely into details.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">My friend</char> insisted upon my accompanying them in their expedition</action>, which I was
                        eager enough to do, for my curiosity and sympathy were deeply stirred by the
                        story to which we had listened. I confess that the guilt of <char
                                gender="male" name="alexanderHolder">the banker</char>’s son
                        appeared to me to be as obvious as it did to his unhappy father, but still I
                        had such faith in <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>’
                        judgment that I felt that there must be some grounds for hope as long as he
                        was dissatisfied with the accepted explanation. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> hardly spoke a word the
                        whole way out to the southern suburb, but sat with his chin upon his breast
                        and his hat drawn over his eyes, sunk in the deepest thought</action>. Our client
                        appeared to have taken fresh heart at the little glimpse of hope which had
                        been presented to him, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> even broke into a desultory chat with me over
                        his business affairs</action>. A short railway journey and a shorter walk brought us
                        to Fairbank, the modest residence of the great financier.</p>
                <p>Fairbank was a good-sized square house of white stone, standing back a little
                        from the road. A double carriage-sweep, with a snow-clad lawn, stretched
                        down in front to two large iron gates which closed the entrance. On the
                        right side was a small wooden thicket, which led into a narrow path between
                        two neat hedges stretching from the road to the kitchen door, and forming
                        the tradesmen’s entrance. On the left ran a lane which led to the stables,
                        and was not itself within the grounds at all, being a public, though little
                        used, thoroughfare. <action><char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes"
                                        >Holmes</char> left us standing at the door and walked
                                slowly all round the house, across the front, down the tradesmen’s
                                path, and so round by the garden behind into the stable
                                lane</action>. So long was he that <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr.
                                Holder</char> and I went into the dining-room and waited by the fire
                        until he should return. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder, johnWatson">We</char> were sitting there in silence</action> when the door
                        opened and <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">a young lady</char> came in</action>. She was rather above the middle height,
                        slim, with dark hair and eyes, which seemed the darker against the absolute
                        pallor of her skin. I do not think that I have ever seen such deadly
                        paleness in a woman’s face. Her lips, too, were bloodless, but her eyes were
                        flushed with crying. As <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> swept silently into the room</action> she impressed me
                        with a greater sense of grief than <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">the banker</char> had
                        done in the morning, and it was the more striking in her as she was
                        evidently a woman of strong character, with immense capacity for
                        self-restraint. <action>Disregarding my presence, <char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> went straight to her uncle and
                        passed her hand over his head with a sweet womanly caress</action>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">You have given orders that <char gender="male"
                                        name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> should be liberated,
                                have you not, dad?</quote> she asked.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">No, no, my girl, the matter must be probed to
                                the bottom.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">But I am so sure that he is innocent. You know what
                                woman’s instincts are. I know that he has done no harm and that you
                                will be sorry for having acted so harshly.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Why is he silent, then, if he is
                                innocent?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Who knows? Perhaps because he was so angry that you
                                should suspect him.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">How could I help suspecting him, when I actually
                                saw him with the coronet in his hand?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Oh, but he had only picked it up to look at it. Oh,
                                do, do take my word for it that he is innocent. Let the matter drop
                                and say no more. It is so dreadful to think of our dear <char
                                        gender="male" name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> in
                                prison!</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I shall never let it drop until the gems are
                                found—never, <char gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Mary</char>! Your affection for
                                        <char gender="male" name = "arthurHolder">Arthur</char> blinds you as to the awful
                        consequences to me. Far from hushing the thing up, <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> have brought a
                                gentleman down from London to inquire more deeply into
                        it.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">This gentleman?</quote> she asked, facing round to
                        me.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">No, his friend. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> wished us to leave him alone</action>.
                                He is round in the stable lane now.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">The stable lane?</quote> <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">She</char> raised her dark
                        eyebrows.</action> <quote speaker="maryHolder">What can he hope to find there? Ah!
                                this, I suppose, is he. I trust, sir, that you will succeed in
                                proving, what I feel sure is the truth, that my cousin <char
                                        gender="male" name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> is
                                innocent of this crime.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I fully share your opinion, and I trust, with
                                you, that we may prove it,</quote> returned <char gender="male"
                                name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, going back to the mat to knock
                        the snow from his shoes. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I believe I have
                                the honour of addressing Miss <char gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Mary
                                        Holder</char>. Might I ask you a question or
                        two?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Pray do, sir, if it may help to clear this horrible
                                affair up.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You heard nothing yourself last
                        night?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Nothing, until my uncle here began to speak loudly.
                        <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">I</char> heard that, and I came down</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You shut up the windows and doors the night
                                before. Did you fasten all the windows?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Yes.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Were they all fastened this morning?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Yes.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You have a maid who has a sweetheart? I think
                                that you remarked to your uncle last night that she had been out to
                                see him?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Yes, and she was the girl who waited in the
                                drawing-room, and who may have heard uncle’s remarks about the
                                coronet.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I see. <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">You</char> infer that she may have gone out to
                                tell her sweetheart, and that the two may have planned the
                                robbery.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">But what is the good of all these vague
                                theories,</quote> cried <char gender="male" name="alexanderHolder"
                                >the banker</char> impatiently, <quote speaker="alexanderHolder"
                                >when I have told you that I saw <char gender="male"
                                        name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> with the coronet in his
                                hands?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Wait a little, <char gender="male"
                                        name="alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>. We must come back
                                to that. About this girl, <char gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Miss Holder</char>.
                                You saw her return by the kitchen door, I presume?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Yes; <action>when <char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">I</char> went to see if the door was fastened
                                for the night I met her slipping in</action>. I saw the man, too, in the
                                gloom.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do you know him?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Oh, yes! he is the greengrocer who brings our
                                vegetables round. His name is <char gender="male" name = "francisProsper">Francis
                                        Prosper</char>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">He stood,</quote> said <char gender="male"
                                name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">to the
                                left of the door—that is to say, farther up the path than is
                                necessary to reach the door?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">Yes, he did.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And he is a man with a wooden leg?</quote></p>
                <p>Something like fear sprang up in the young lady’s expressive black eyes. <quote
                                speaker="maryHolder">Why, you are like a magician,</quote> said
                        she. <quote speaker="maryHolder">How do you know that?</quote> She smiled,
                        but there was no answering smile in <char gender="male"
                                name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>’ thin, eager face.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I should be very glad now to go upstairs,</quote>
                        said he. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I shall probably wish to go over the
                                outside of the house again. Perhaps I had better take a look at the
                                lower windows before I go up.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> walked swiftly round from one to the other, pausing only at the large one
                        which looked from the hall onto the stable lane. This he opened and made a
                        very careful examination of the sill with his powerful magnifying lens.</action>
                                <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Now we shall go upstairs,</quote>
                        said he at last.</p>
                <p>The banker’s dressing-room was a plainly furnished little chamber, with a grey
                        carpet, a large bureau, and a long mirror. <action><char gender="male"
                                name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> went to the bureau first and
                        looked hard at the lock.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Which key was used to open it?</quote> he
                        asked.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">That which my son himself indicated—that of the
                                cupboard of the lumber-room.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Have you it here?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">That is it on the dressing-table.</quote></p>
                <p><action>Sherlock <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> took it up and
                        opened the bureau.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is a noiseless lock,</quote> said he. <quote
                                speaker="sherlockHolmes"> It is no wonder that it did not wake you.
                                This case, I presume, contains the coronet. We must have a look at
                                it.</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> opened the case, and taking out the diadem he laid it
                        upon the table.</action> It was a magnificent specimen of the jeweller’s art, and the
                        thirty-six stones were the finest that I have ever seen. At one side of the
                        coronet was a cracked edge, where a corner holding three gems had been torn
                        away.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Now, <char gender="male" name="alexanderHolder"
                                        >Mr. Holder</char>,</quote> said <char gender="male" name = "sherlockHolmes">
                                Holmes</char>, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">here is the corner
                                which corresponds to that which has been so unfortunately lost.
                                Might I beg that you will break it off.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">The banker</char> recoiled in horror</action>. <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I should not
                                dream of trying,</quote> said he.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Then I will.</quote>
                        <action><char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> suddenly bent his
                        strength upon it, but without result.</action> <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I feel
                                it give a little,</quote> said he; <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">but,
                                though I am exceptionally strong in the fingers, it would take me
                                all my time to break it. An ordinary man could not do it. Now, what
                                do you think would happen if I did break it, <char gender="male"
                                        name="alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>? There would be a
                                noise like a pistol shot. Do you tell me that all this happened
                                within a few yards of your bed and that you heard nothing of
                                it?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I do not know what to think. It is all dark to
                                me.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">But perhaps it may grow lighter as we go. What do
                                you think, <char gender="female" name = "maryHolder">Miss Holder</char>?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="maryHolder">I confess that I still share my uncle’s
                                perplexity.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your son had no shoes or slippers on when you saw
                                him?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">He had nothing on save only his trousers and
                                shirt.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Thank you. We have certainly been favoured with
                                extraordinary luck during this inquiry, and it will be entirely our
                                own fault if we do not succeed in clearing the matter up. With your
                                permission, <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>, I shall now
                                continue my investigations outside.</quote></p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> went alone, at his own request, for he explained that any unnecessary
                        footmarks might make his task more difficult</action>. For an hour or more <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> was at
                        work, returning at last with his feet heavy with snow and his features as
                        inscrutable as ever.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I think that I have seen now all that there is to
                                see, <char gender="male" name = "alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>,</quote> said he; <quote
                                speaker="sherlockHolmes">I can serve you best by returning to my
                                rooms.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">But the gems, Mr. <char gender="male"
                                        name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>. Where are
                        they?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I cannot tell.</quote></p>
                <p>The banker wrung his hands. <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I shall never see
                                them again!</quote> he cried. <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">And
                                my son? You give me hopes?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">My opinion is in no way altered.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Then, for God’s sake, what was this dark
                                business which was acted in my house last night?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">If you can call upon me at my Baker Street rooms
                                to-morrow morning between nine and ten I shall be happy to do what I
                                can to make it clearer. I understand that you give me _carte
                                blanche_ to act for you, provided only that I get back the gems, and
                                that you place no limit on the sum I may draw.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I would give my fortune to have them
                                back.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Very good. I shall look into the matter between
                                this and then. Good-bye; it is just possible that I may have to come
                                over here again before evening.</quote></p>
                <p>It was obvious to me that my companion’s mind was now made up about the case,
                        although what his conclusions were was more than I could even dimly imagine.
                        Several times during our homeward journey I endeavoured to sound him upon
                        the point, but he always glided away to some other topic, until at last I
                        gave it over in despair. It was not yet three when we found ourselves in our
                        rooms once more. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> hurried to his chamber and was down again in a few
                        minutes dressed as a common loafer.</action> With his collar turned up, his shiny,
                        seedy coat, his red cravat, and his worn boots, he was a perfect sample of
                        the class.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I think that this should do,</quote> <action>said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char>,
                        glancing into the glass above the fireplace</action>. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"
                                >I only wish that you could come with me, <char gender="male" name = "johnWatson">
                                        Watson</char>, but I fear that it won’t do. I may be on the
                                trail in this matter, or I may be following a will-o’-the-wisp, but
                                I shall soon know which it is. I hope that I may be back in a few
                                hours.</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> cut a slice of beef from the joint upon the
                        sideboard, sandwiched it between two rounds of bread, and thrusting this
                        rude meal into his pocket he started off upon his expedition.</action></p>
                <p>I had just finished my tea when he returned, evidently in excellent spirits,
                        swinging an old elastic-sided boot in his hand. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> chucked it down into a
                        corner and helped himself to a cup of tea.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I only looked in as I passed,</quote> said he.
                                <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I am going right on.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Where to?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Oh, to the other side of the West End. It may be
                                some time before I get back. Don’t wait up for me in case I should
                                be late.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">How are you getting on?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Oh, so so. Nothing to complain of. I have been
                                out to Streatham since I saw you last, but I did not call at the
                                house. It is a very sweet little problem, and I would not have
                                missed it for a good deal. However, I must not sit gossiping here,
                                but must get these disreputable clothes off and return to my highly
                                respectable self.</quote></p>
                <p>I could see by his manner that he had stronger reasons for satisfaction than his
                        words alone would imply. His eyes twinkled, and there was even a touch of
                        colour upon his sallow cheeks. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> hastened upstairs, and a few minutes later
                        I heard the slam of the hall door</action>, which told me that he was off once more
                        upon his congenial hunt.</p>
                <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> waited until midnight, but there was no sign of his return, so I retired to my
                        room</action>. It was no uncommon thing for him to be away for days and nights on end
                        when he was hot upon a scent, so that his lateness caused me no surprise. I
                        do not know at what hour he came in, but when I came down to breakfast in
                        the morning there he was with a cup of coffee in one hand and the paper in
                        the other, as fresh and trim as possible.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You will excuse my beginning without you, <char
                                        gender="male" name="johnWatson"> Watson</char>,</quote> said
                        he, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">but you remember that our client has
                                rather an early appointment this morning.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Why, it is after nine now,</quote> I answered. <quote
                                speaker="johnWatson">I should not be surprised if that were he. I
                                thought I heard a ring.</quote></p>
                <p>It was, indeed, our friend <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">the financier</char>. I was shocked by the change which had
                        come over him, for his face which was naturally of a broad and massive
                        mould, was now pinched and fallen in, while his hair seemed to me at least a
                        shade whiter. <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">He</char> entered with a weariness and lethargy which was even more
                        painful than his violence of the morning before, and he dropped heavily into
                        the armchair which I pushed forward for him.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I do not know what I have done to be so severely
                                tried,</quote> said he. <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Only two
                                days ago I was a happy and prosperous man, without a care in the
                                world. Now I am left to a lonely and dishonoured age. One sorrow
                                comes close upon the heels of another. My niece, <action><char
                                                gender="female" name="maryHolder"> Mary</char>,
                                        has deserted me</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Deserted you?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Yes. Her bed this morning had not been slept in,
                                her room was empty, and a note for me lay upon the hall table. I had
                                said to her last night, in sorrow and not in anger, that if she had
                                married my boy all might have been well with him. Perhaps it was
                                thoughtless of me to say so. It is to that remark that she refers in
                                this note:</quote></p>
                <p>
                        <quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="maryHolder">MY DEAREST
                                        UNCLE,—I feel that I have brought trouble upon you, and that
                                        if I had acted differently this terrible misfortune might
                                        never have occurred. I cannot, with this thought in my mind,
                                        ever again be happy under your roof, and I feel that I must
                                        leave you forever. Do not worry about my future, for that is
                                        provided for; and, above all, do not search for me, for it
                                        will be fruitless labour and an ill-service to me. In life
                                        or in death, I am ever your loving,</subq></quote></p>
                <p>
                        <quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><subq speaker="maryHolder"><char
                                                gender="female" name="maryHolder">
                                        MARY</char>.</subq></quote></p>
                <p>
                        <quote speaker="alexanderHolder">What could she mean by that note, Mr. <char
                                        gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes"> Holmes</char>? Do you
                                think it points to suicide?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, no, nothing of the kind. It is perhaps the
                                best possible solution. I trust, <char gender="male"
                                        name="alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>, that you are
                                nearing the end of your troubles.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Ha! You say so! You have heard something, Mr.
                                        <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes"> Holmes</char>;
                                you have learned something! Where are the gems?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You would not think £ 1000 apiece an excessive
                                sum for them?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I would pay ten.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">That would be unnecessary. Three thousand will
                                cover the matter. And there is a little reward, I fancy. Have you
                                your cheque-book? Here is a pen. Better make it out for £
                                4000.</quote></p>
                <p>With a dazed face <char gender="male" name="alexanderHolder">the banker</char>
                        made out the required check. <action><char gender="male"
                                        name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> walked over to his desk,
                                took out a little triangular piece of gold with three gems in it,
                                and threw it down upon the table</action>.</p>
                <p><action>With a shriek of joy <char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">our client</char> clutched it up.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">You have it!</quote> he gasped. <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">I am saved! I am saved!</quote></p>
                <p>The reaction of joy was as passionate as his grief had been, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">he</char> hugged his
                        recovered gems to his bosom.</action></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There is one other thing you owe, <char
                                        gender="male" name="alexanderHolder">Mr.
                                Holder</char>,</quote> said Sherlock <char gender="male"
                                name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> rather sternly.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Owe!</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">He</char> caught up a pen.</action> <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">Name the sum, and I will pay
                        it.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, the debt is not to me. You owe a very humble
                                apology to that noble lad, your son, who has carried himself in this
                                matter as I should be proud to see my own son do, should I ever
                                chance to have one.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Then it was not <char gender="male"
                                        name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> who took
                        them?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I told you yesterday, and I repeat to-day, that
                                it was not.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">You are sure of it! Then let us hurry to him at
                                once to let him know that the truth is known.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">He knows it already. When I had cleared it all up
                                I had an interview with him, and finding that he would not tell me
                                the story, I told it to him, on which <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char> had to confess that I was
                                right and to add the very few details which were not yet quite clear
                                to me</action>. Your news of this morning, however, may open his
                                lips.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">For Heaven’s sake, tell me, then, what is this
                                extraordinary mystery!</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I will do so, and I will show you the steps by
                                which I reached it. And let me say to you, first, that which it is
                                hardest for me to say and for you to hear: there has been an
                                understanding between Sir George <char gender="male"
                                        name="georgeBurnwell"> Burnwell</char> and your niece <char
                                        gender="female" name="maryHolder">Mary</char>. They have
                                now fled together.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">My <char gender="female" name="maryHolder"
                                        >Mary</char>? Impossible!</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is unfortunately more than possible; it is
                                certain. Neither you nor your son knew the true character of this
                                man when you admitted him into your family circle. He is one of the
                                most dangerous men in England—a ruined gambler, an absolutely
                                desperate villain, a man without heart or conscience. Your niece
                                knew nothing of such men. When he breathed his vows to her, as he
                                had done to a hundred before her, <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> flattered herself that she
                                alone had touched his heart.</action> The devil knows best what he said, but
                                at least she became his tool and was in the habit of seeing him
                                nearly every evening.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">I cannot, and I will not, believe it!</quote>
                        cried <char gender="male" name="alexanderHolder">the banker</char> with an
                        ashen face.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I will tell you, then, what occurred in your
                        house last night. <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">Your niece</char>, when you had, as she thought, gone to
                                your room, slipped down and talked to her lover through the window
                                which leads into the stable lane</action>. His footmarks had pressed right
                        through the snow, so long had he stood there. <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">She</char> told him of the
                                coronet.</action> His wicked lust for gold kindled at the news, and he bent
                                her to his will. I have no doubt that she loved you, but there are
                                women in whom the love of a lover extinguishes all other loves, and
                                I think that she must have been one. She had hardly listened to his
                                instructions when she saw you coming downstairs, on which <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> closed
                                the window rapidly and told you about one of the servants’ escapade
                                with her wooden-legged lover</action>, which was all perfectly
                        true.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your boy, <action><char gender="male"
                                                name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char>, went to bed
                                        after his interview with you but he slept badly on account
                                        of his uneasiness about his club debts.</action> In the middle of the
                                        night <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char> heard a soft tread pass his door, so he rose and,
                                                looking out</action>, was surprised to see <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">his cousin</char> walking very
                                        stealthily along the passage until she disappeared into your
                                        dressing-room</action>. Petrified with astonishment, <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">the lad</char> slipped
                                        on some clothes and waited there in the dark</action> to see what
                        would come of this strange affair. Presently <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char>
                                emerged from the room again</action>, and in the light of the passage-lamp
                        <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">your son</char> saw that she carried the precious coronet in her hands</action>. <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">She</char>
                                passed down the stairs</action>, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">he</char>, thrilling with horror, ran along and
                                slipped behind the curtain near your door, whence he could see what
                                passed in the hall beneath</action>. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> saw her</action> <action>stealthily open the window,
                                hand out the coronet to someone in the gloom, and then closing it
                                once more hurry back to <char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">her</char> room, passing quite close to where he
                                stood hid behind the curtain</action>.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">As long as she was on the scene he could not take
                                any action without a horrible exposure of the woman whom he loved.
                                But the instant that she was gone he realised how crushing a
                                misfortune this would be for you, and how all-important it was to
                                set it right. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> rushed down, just as he was, in his bare feet,
                                opened the window, sprang out into the snow, and ran down the lane,
                                where he could see a dark figure in the moonlight</action>. Sir George
                                                <action><char gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell">
                                                Burnwell</char> tried to get away</action>, but
                                                <action><char gender="male" name="arthurHolder"
                                                >Arthur</char> caught him, and there was a struggle
                                        between them, your lad tugging at one side of the coronet,
                                        and his opponent at the other</action>. In the scuffle, <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">your
                                son</char> struck</action> <char gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell">Sir
                                        George</char> and <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">cut him over the eye</char></action>. Then something
                        suddenly snapped, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">your son</char>, finding that he had the coronet in
                                his hands, rushed back, closed the window, ascended to your room,
                                and had just observed that the coronet had been twisted in the
                                struggle and was endeavouring to straighten it</action> when you appeared
                                upon the scene.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">Is it possible?</quote> gasped <char
                                gender="male" name="alexanderHolder">the banker</char>.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">You</char> then roused his anger by calling him names</action> at
                                a moment when he felt that he had deserved your warmest thanks. He
                                could not explain the true state of affairs without betraying one
                                who certainly deserved little enough consideration at his hands. He
                                took the more chivalrous view, however, and preserved her
                                secret.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">And that was why <action><char gender = "female" name = "maryHolder">she</char> shrieked and fainted when
                                she saw the coronet</action>,</quote> cried <char gender="male"
                                name="alexanderHolder">Mr. Holder</char>. <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">Oh, my God! what a blind fool I have been!
                                And his asking to be allowed to go out for five minutes! The dear
                                fellow wanted to see if the missing piece were at the scene of the
                                struggle. How cruelly I have misjudged him!</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">When I arrived at the house,</quote> continued
                                <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote
                                speaker="sherlockHolmes">I at once went very carefully round it to
                                observe if there were any traces in the snow which might help me. I
                                knew that none had fallen since the evening before, and also that
                                there had been a strong frost to preserve impressions. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> passed
                                along the tradesmen’s path, but found it all trampled down and
                                indistinguishable</action>. Just beyond it, however, at the far side of the
                                        kitchen door, <action><char gender = "female" name = "lucyParr">a woman</char> had stood and talked with a man</action>, whose round
                                impressions on one side showed that he had a wooden leg. I could
                                even tell that they had been disturbed, for the woman had run back
                                swiftly to the door, as was shown by the deep toe and light heel
                                marks, while Wooden-leg had waited a little, and then had gone away.
                                I thought at the time that this might be the maid and her
                                sweetheart, of whom you had already spoken to me, and inquiry showed
                                it was so. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> passed round the garden without seeing anything more
                                than random tracks</action>, which I took to be the police; but when I got
                                into the stable lane a very long and complex story was written in
                                the snow in front of me.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There was a double line of tracks of a booted
                        man, and a second double line which <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> saw with delight</action> belonged to a
                        man with naked feet. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> was at once convinced from what you had told
                                me that the latter was your son</action>. The first had walked both ways, but
                                the other had run swiftly, and as his tread was marked in places
                                over the depression of the boot, it was obvious that he had passed
                                after the other. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> followed them up and found they led to the hall
                                        window</action>, where Boots had worn all the snow away while waiting. Then <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char>
                                walked to the other end, which was a hundred yards or more down the
                                lane. I saw where Boots had faced round</action>, where the snow was cut up
                                as though there had been a struggle, and, finally, where a few drops
                                of blood had fallen, to show me that I was not mistaken. <action><char gender = "male" name = "georgeBurnwell">Boots</char> had
                                then run down the lane</action>, and another little smudge of blood showed
                        that it was he who had been hurt. When <action><char gender = "male" name = "georgeBurnwell">he</char> came to the highroad at
                                the other end</action>, I found that the pavement had been cleared, so there
                                was an end to that clue.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"><action>On entering the house, however, <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> examined, as
                                you remember, the sill and framework of the hall window with my
                                lens,</action> and <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> could at once see that someone had passed out. I could
                                distinguish the outline of an instep where the wet foot had been
                                placed in coming in. I was then beginning to be able to form an
                                opinion as to what had occurred</action>. A man had waited outside the
                                window; someone had brought the gems; the deed had been overseen by
                                your son; he had pursued the thief; had struggled with him; they had
                                each tugged at the coronet, their united strength causing injuries
                                which neither alone could have effected. <action><char gender = "male" name = "arthurHolder">He</char> had returned with the
                                prize, but had left a fragment in the grasp of his opponent</action>. So far
                                I was clear. The question now was, who was the man and who was it
                                brought him the coronet?</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is an old maxim of mine that when you have
                                excluded the impossible, whatever remains, however improbable, must
                                be the truth. Now, I knew that it was not you who had brought it
                                down, so there only remained your niece and the maids. But if it
                                were the maids, why should your son allow himself to be accused in
                                their place? There could be no possible reason. As he loved his
                                cousin, however, there was an excellent explanation why he should
                                retain her secret—the more so as the secret was a disgraceful one.
                                When <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> remembered that you had seen her at that window, and how she
                                had fainted on seeing the coronet again</action>, my conjecture became a
                                certainty.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And who could it be who was her confederate? A
                                lover evidently, for who else could outweigh the love and gratitude
                                which she must feel to you? I knew that you went out little, and
                                that your circle of friends was a very limited one. But among them
                                was Sir George <char gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell"
                                        >Burnwell</char>. I had heard of him before as being a man
                        of evil reputation among women. It must have been <action><char gender = "male" name = "georgeBurnwell">he</char> who wore those
                                boots and retained the missing gems.</action> Even though he knew that <char
                                        gender="male" name="arthurHolder">Arthur</char> had
                                discovered him, he might still flatter himself that he was safe, for
                                the lad could not say a word without compromising his own
                                family.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Well, your own good sense will suggest what
                        measures I took next. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> went in the shape of a loafer</action> to <char
                                        gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell">Sir George</char>’s
                                house, <action>managed to pick up an acquaintance with his valet, learned
                                that his master had cut his head the night before, and, finally, at
                                the expense of six shillings, made all sure by buying a pair of his
                                cast-off shoes. With these <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> journeyed down to Streatham and saw
                                that they exactly fitted the tracks.</action></quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder"><action><char gender = "male" name = "alexanderHolder">I</char> saw an ill-dressed vagabond in the lane
                                yesterday evening</action>,</quote> said Mr. Holder.</p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Precisely. It was I. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> found that I had my man,
                                so I came home and changed my clothes</action>. It was a delicate part which
                        I had to play then, for <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> saw that a prosecution must be avoided to
                                avert scandal, and I knew that so astute a villain would see that
                                our hands were tied in the matter. I went and saw him.</action> At first, of
                        course, <action><char gender = "male" name = "georgeBurnwell">he</char> denied everything</action>. But when <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> gave him every particular
                                that had occurred</action>, <action><char gender = "male" name = "georgeBurnwell">he</char> tried to bluster and took down a
                                        life-preserver from the wall</action>. I knew my man, however, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> clapped
                                a pistol to his head before he could strike</action>. Then he became a little
                        more reasonable. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> told him that we would give him a price for the
                                stones he held—£ 1000 apiece</action>. That brought out the first signs of
                                grief that he had shown. <subq speaker="georgeBurnwell">Why, dash it
                                        all!</subq> said he, <subq speaker="georgeBurnwell">I’ve let
                                                them go at six hundred for the three!</subq> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> soon managed
                                to get the address of the receiver who had them, on promising him
                                that there would be no prosecution.</action> <action>Off <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> set to him, and after much
                                chaffering I got our stones at £ 1000 apiece. Then I looked in upon
                                your son, told him that all was right, and eventually got to my bed
                                about two o’clock</action>, after what I may call a really hard day’s
                                work.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="alexanderHolder">A day which has saved England from a great
                                public scandal,</quote> said the banker, rising. <quote
                                speaker="alexanderHolder">Sir, I cannot find words to thank you, but
                                you shall not find me ungrateful for what you have done. Your skill
                                has indeed exceeded all that I have heard of it. And now I must fly
                                to my dear boy to apologise to him for the wrong which I have done
                                him. As to what you tell me of poor <char gender="female"
                                        name="maryHolder">Mary</char>, it goes to my very heart.
                                Not even your skill can inform me where she is now.</quote></p>
                <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I think that we may safely say,</quote> returned
                                <char gender="male" name="sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote
                                speaker="sherlockHolmes">that she is wherever Sir George <char
                                        gender="male" name="georgeBurnwell">Burnwell</char> is. It
                                is equally certain, too, that whatever her sins are, they will soon
                                receive a more than sufficient punishment.</quote></p>
        </story>
</passage>
