<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<passage>
<chapter number ="5">V.</chapter> <title>THE FIVE ORANGE PIPS</title>

<story>
When I glance over my notes and records of the <char gender="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> cases
between the years ’82 and ’90, I am faced by so many which present
strange and interesting features that it is no easy matter to know
which to choose and which to leave. Some, however, have already gained
publicity through the papers, and others have not offered a field for
those peculiar qualities which <char gender="male">my friend</char> possessed in so high a degree,
and which it is the object of these papers to illustrate. Some, too,
<action char = "sherlock">have baffled his analytical skill, and would be, as narratives,
beginnings without an ending, while others have been but partially
cleared up, and have their explanations founded rather upon conjecture
and surmise than on that absolute logical proof which was so dear to
him.</action> There is, however, one of these last which was so remarkable in
its details and so startling in its results that I am tempted to give
some account of it in spite of the fact that there are points in
connection with it which never have been, and probably never will be,
entirely cleared up.


The year ’87 furnished us with a long series of cases of greater or
less interest, of which I retain the records. Among my headings under
this one twelve months I find an account of the adventure of the
Paradol Chamber, of the Amateur Mendicant Society, who held a luxurious
club in the lower vault of a furniture warehouse, of the facts
connected with the loss of the British barque <char gender="female">Sophy Anderson</char>, of the
singular adventures of the Grice Patersons in the island of Uffa, and
finally of the Camberwell poisoning case. In the latter, as may be
remembered, <char gender="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> <action char = "sherlock">was able, by winding up the <char gender = "male">dead man’s</char>
watch, to prove that it had been wound up two hours before, and that
therefore the deceased had gone to bed within that time—a deduction
which was of the greatest importance in clearing up the case.</action> All these
I may sketch out at some future date, but none of them present such
singular features as the strange train of circumstances which I have
now taken up my pen to describe.


It was in the latter days of September, and the equinoctial gales had
set in with exceptional violence. All day the wind had screamed and the
rain had beaten against the windows, so that even here in the heart of
great, hand-made London we were forced to raise our minds for the
instant from the routine of life and to recognise the presence of those
great elemental forces which shriek at mankind through the bars of his
civilisation, like untamed beasts in a cage. As evening drew in, the
storm grew higher and louder, and the wind cried and sobbed like a
child in the chimney. <char gender="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> <action char = "sherlock">sat moodily at one side of the
fireplace cross-indexing his records of crime,</action><action char = "watson"> while I at the other was
deep in one of <char gender="male">Clark Russell’s</char> fine sea-stories until the howl of the
gale from without seemed to blend with the text, and the splash of the
rain to lengthen out into the long swash of the sea waves.</action> <char gender="female">My wife</char><action char = "mary"> was
on a visit to <char gender="female">her mother’s</char>,</action><action char = "watson"> and for a few days I was a dweller once
more in my old quarters at Baker Street.</action>


<quote speaker ="watson">“Why,”</quote> said I, glancing up at my companion, <quote speaker ="watson">“that was surely the bell.
Who could come to-night? Some friend of yours, perhaps?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Except yourself I have none,”</quote> he answered. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“I do not encourage
visitors.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“A client, then?”</quote>

<quote char = "mr_turner">“If so, it is a serious case. Nothing less would bring a man out on
such a day and at such an hour. But I take it that it is more likely to
be some crony of the landlady’s.”</quote>

<char gender="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> was wrong in his conjecture, however, for there came a
step in the passage and a tapping at the door. <action char = "sherlock">He stretched out his
long arm to turn the lamp away from himself and towards the vacant
chair upon which a newcomer must sit.</action>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Come in!”</quote> said he.

    
<char gender="male">The man who entered was young, some two-and-twenty at the outside,
well-groomed and trimly clad, with something of refinement and delicacy
in his bearing. The streaming umbrella which he held in his hand, and
his long shining waterproof told of the fierce weather through which he
had come. He looked about him anxiously in the glare of the lamp, and I
could see that his face was pale and his eyes heavy, like those of a
man who is weighed down with some great anxiety.</char>

    
<quote speaker = "john">“I owe you an apology,”</quote> he said, raising his golden pince-nez to his
eyes. <quote speaker = "john">“I trust that I am not intruding. I fear that I have brought some
traces of the storm and rain into your snug chamber.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Give me your coat and umbrella,”</quote> said Holmes. <quote speaker = "sherlock">“They may rest here on
the hook and will be dry presently. You have come up from the
south-west, I see.”</quote>


<quote speaker = "john">“Yes, from Horsham.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“That clay and chalk mixture which I see upon your toe caps is quite
distinctive.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“I have come for advice.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“That is easily got.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“And help.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“That is not always so easy.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“I have heard of you, <char gender="male">Mr. Holmes</char>. I heard from <char gender = "male">Major Prendergast</char> how
you saved him in the Tankerville Club scandal.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Ah, of course. <char gender="male">He</char> was wrongfully accused of cheating at cards.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“<char gender="male">He</char> said that <action char = "sherlock">you could solve anything</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“He said too much.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“That you are never beaten.”</quote> 

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“<char gender="male">I</char> have <action char="men">been beaten four times—three times by <char gender="male">men</char></action>, 
and once <action char="woman">by a woman</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“But what is that compared with the number of your successes?”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“It is true that I have been generally successful.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“Then you may be so with me.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“I beg that you will draw your chair up to the fire and favour me with
some details as to your case.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“It is no ordinary one.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“None of those which come to me are. I am the last court of appeal.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“And yet <action char = "john"><char gender="male">I</char> question, sir, whether, in all your experience, you have
ever listened to a more mysterious and inexplicable chain of events
than those which have happened in my own family</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“You fill me with interest,”</quote> said Holmes. <quote speaker = "sherlock">“Pray give us the essential
facts from the commencement, and I can afterwards question you as to
those details which seem to me to be most important.”</quote>

<action char="john">The young man pulled his chair up and pushed his wet feet out towards
the blaze.</action>

        
<quote speaker ="john">“My name,” said he, “is John Openshaw, but my own affairs have, as far
as I can understand, little to do with this awful business. It is a
hereditary matter; so in order to give you an idea of the facts, I must
go back to the commencement of the affair.</quote>
   
“You must know that my <char gender ="male">grandfather</char> had two sons—<char gender ="male">my uncle Elias</char> and my
<char gender ="male">father Joseph</char>. <action char = "joseph">My father had a small factory at Coventry, which he
enlarged at the time of the invention of bicycling. He was a patentee
of the Openshaw unbreakable tire, and his business met with such
success that he was able to sell it and to retire upon a handsome
competence.</action>
    
    
“My <char gender ="male">uncle Elias</char> <action char ="elias">emigrated to America when he was a young man and became
a planter in Florida, where he was reported to have done very well. At
the time of the war he fought in <char gender="male">Jackson’s</char> army, and afterwards under
<char gender="male">Hood</char>, where he rose to be a colonel. When <char gender="male">Lee</char> laid down his arms my
<char gender="male">uncle</char> returned to his plantation, where he remained for three or four
years. About 1869 or 1870 he came back to Europe and took a small
estate in Sussex, near Horsham. He had made a very considerable fortune
in the States, and his reason for leaving them was his aversion to the
negroes, and his dislike of the Republican policy in extending the
franchise to them. He was a singular man, fierce and quick-tempered,
very foul-mouthed when he was angry, and of a most retiring
disposition.</action><action char="elias"> During all the years that he lived at Horsham, I doubt if
ever he set foot in the town. He had a garden and two or three fields
round his house, and there he would take his exercise, though very
often for weeks on end he would never leave his room. He drank a great
deal of brandy and smoked very heavily, but he would see no society and
did not want any friends, not even his own <char gender ="male">brother</char>.</action>

“<action char ="elias">He didn’t mind <char gender = "male">me</char>; in fact, he took a fancy to me, for at the time
when he saw me first I was a youngster of twelve or so. This would be
in the year 1878, after he had been eight or nine years in England. He
begged my father to let me live with him and he was very kind to me in
his way. When he was sober he used to be fond of playing backgammon and
draughts with me, and he would make me his representative both with the
servants and with the tradespeople,</action> <action char ="john"> so that by the time that I was
sixteen I was quite master of the house. I kept all the keys and could
go where I liked and do what I liked, so long as I did not disturb him
in his privacy</action>. There was one singular exception, however, <action char ="elias">for he had a
single room, a lumber-room up among the attics, which was invariably
locked, and which he would never permit either me or anyone else to
enter</action>. <action char ="john">With a boy’s curiosity I have peeped through the keyhole, but I
was never able to see more than such a collection of old trunks and
bundles as would be expected in such a room</action>.

“One day—it was in March, 1883—a letter with a foreign stamp lay upon
the table in front of the <char gender = "male">colonel’s</char> plate. It was not a common thing
for him to receive letters, for his bills were all paid in ready money,
and he had no friends of any sort. <quote speaker ="elias">‘From India!’</quote> said he as he took it
up, <quote speaker ="elias">‘Pondicherry postmark! What can this be?’</quote> <action char ="elias">Opening it hurriedly, out
there jumped five little dried orange pips, which pattered down upon
his plate.</action> <action char ="john">I began to laugh at this, but the laugh was struck from my
lips at the sight of his face</action>. <action char ="elias">His lip had fallen, his eyes were
protruding, his skin the colour of putty, and he glared at the envelope
which he still held in his trembling hand</action>, <quote speaker ="elias">‘K. K. K.!’</quote> he shrieked, and
then, <quote speaker ="colonel">‘My God, my God, my sins have overtaken me!’</quote>

<quote speaker="john">“‘What is it, <char gender="male">uncle</char>?’</quote> I cried.

<quote speaker ="elias">“‘Death,’</quote> said he, and <action char ="elias">rising from the table he retired to his room,</action>
<action char ="john">leaving me palpitating with horror. I took up the envelope and saw
scrawled in red ink upon the inner flap, just above the gum, the letter
K three times repeated. There was nothing else save the five dried
pips. What could be the reason of his overpowering terror? I left the
breakfast-table, and as I ascended the stair I met </action><action char ="elias">him coming down with
an old rusty key, which must have belonged to the attic, in one hand,
and a small brass box, like a cashbox, in the other</action>.

<quote speaker ="elias">“‘They may do what they like, but I’ll checkmate them still,’</quote> said he
with an oath. <quote speaker ="elias">‘Tell <char gender ="female">Mary</char> that I shall want a fire in my room to-day,
and send down to <char gender ="male">Fordham, the Horsham lawyer</char>.’</quote>

“<action char ="john">I did as he ordered, and when the lawyer arrived I was asked to step
up to the room. The fire was burning brightly, and in the grate there
was a mass of black, fluffy ashes, as of burned paper, while the brass
box stood open and empty beside it. As I glanced at the box I noticed,
with a start, that upon the lid was printed the treble K which I had
read in the morning upon the envelope</action>.

<quote speaker ="elias">“‘I wish you, John,’</quote> said my uncle, <quote speaker ="elias">‘to witness my will. <action char ="elias">I leave my
estate, with all its advantages and all its disadvantages, <char gender ="male">to my
brother</char>, <char gender ="male">your father</char>, whence it will, no doubt, descend to <char gender ="male">you</char></action>. If you
can enjoy it in peace, well and good! If you find you cannot, take my
advice, my boy, and leave it to your deadliest enemy. I am sorry to
give you such a two-edged thing, but I can’t say what turn things are
going to take. Kindly sign the paper where <char gender ="male">Mr. Fordham</char> shows you.’</quote>

“<action char ="john">I signed the paper as directed</action>, and <action char ="fordham">the lawyer took it away with him</action>.
The singular incident made, as you may think, the deepest impression
upon me, and I pondered over it and turned it every way in my mind
without being able to make anything of it. Yet I could not shake off
the vague feeling of dread which it left behind, though the sensation
grew less keen as the weeks passed and nothing happened to disturb the
usual routine of our lives. I could see a change in my uncle, however.
<action char ="elias">He drank more than ever, and he was less inclined for any sort of
society. Most of his time he would spend in his room, with the door
locked upon the inside, but sometimes he would emerge in a sort of
drunken frenzy and would burst out of the house and tear about the
garden with a revolver in his hand, screaming out that he was afraid of
no man, and that <char gender ="male">he</char> was not to be cooped up, like a sheep in a pen, by
man or devil. When these hot fits were over, however, he would rush
tumultuously in at the door and lock and bar it behind him, like a man
who can brazen it out no longer against the terror which lies at the
roots of his soul</action>. At such times I have seen <char gender ="male">his</char> face, even on a cold
day, glisten with moisture, as though it were new raised from a basin.
   
“Well, to come to an end of the matter, <char gender ="male">Mr. Holmes</char>, and not to abuse
your patience, there came a night when <action char ="elias">he made one of those drunken
sallies from which he never came back</action>. We found <char gender ="male">him</char>, when we went to
search for <char gender ="male">him</char>, face downward in a little green-scummed pool, which lay
at the foot of the garden. There was no sign of any violence, and the
water was but two feet deep, so that the jury, having regard to <char gender ="male">his</char>
known eccentricity, brought in a verdict of ‘suicide.’ But I, who knew
how <action char ="elias">he winced from the very thought of death, had much ado to persuade
myself that he had gone out of his way to meet it. </action>The matter passed,
however, and my <action speaker ="joseph">father entered into possession of the estate, and of
some £ 14,000, which lay to his credit at the bank</action>.”

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“One moment,”</quote> Holmes interposed, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“your statement is, I foresee, one of
the most remarkable to which I have ever listened. Let me have the date
of the reception by your <char gender ="male">uncle</char> of the letter, and the date of <action char ="elias">his
supposed suicide</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“The letter arrived on March 10, 1883. <char gender = "male">His</char> death was seven weeks later,
upon the night of May 2nd.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Thank you. Pray proceed.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“When my <char gender ="male">father</char> took over the Horsham property, <action char ="joseph">he, at my request, made
a careful examination of the attic, which had been always locked up. We
found the brass box there, although its contents had been destroyed. On
the inside of the cover was a paper label, with the initials of K. K.
K. repeated upon it, and ‘Letters, memoranda, receipts, and a register’
written beneath</action>.These, we presume, indicated the nature of the papers
which had been destroyed by Colonel Openshaw. For the rest, there was
nothing of much importance in the attic save a great many scattered
papers and note-books bearing upon my <char gender ="male">uncle’s</char> life in America. Some of
them were of the war time and showed that he had done his duty well and
had borne the repute of a brave soldier. Others were of a date during
the reconstruction of the Southern states, and were mostly concerned
with politics, for he had evidently taken a strong part in opposing the
carpet-bag politicians who had been sent down from the North.

“Well, it was the beginning of ’84 when <action char ="father"><char gender ="male">my father</char> came to live at
Horsham</action>, and all went as well as possible with us until the January of
’85. On the fourth day after the new year I heard <char gender = "male">my father</char> give a
sharp cry of surprise as we sat together at the breakfast-table. There
he was, sitting with a newly opened envelope in one hand and five dried
orange pips in the outstretched palm of the other one. <action char ="joseph">He had always
laughed at what he called my cock-and-bull story about the colonel, but
he looked very scared and puzzled now that the same thing had come upon
himself</action>.
   
<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘Why, what on earth does this mean, John?’</quote> he stammered.

<quote speaker ="john">“My heart had turned to lead. ‘It is K. K. K.,’</quote> said I.

<quote speaker ="joseph">“He looked inside the envelope. ‘So it is,’ he cried. ‘Here are the
very letters. But what is this written above them?’</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“‘Put the papers on the sundial,’</quote> I read, peeping over his shoulder.

<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘What papers? What sundial?’</quote> he asked.

<quote speaker ="john">“‘The sundial in the garden. There is no other,’</quote> said I; <quote speaker ="watson">‘but the
papers must be those that are destroyed.’</quote>

<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘Pooh!’</quote> said he, gripping hard at his courage. <quote speaker ="sherlock">‘We are in a civilised
land here, and we can’t have tomfoolery of this kind. Where does the
thing come from?’</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“‘From Dundee,’</quote> I answered, glancing at the postmark.

<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘Some preposterous practical joke,’</quote> said he. <quote speaker ="sherlock">‘What have I to do with
sundials and papers? I shall take no notice of such nonsense.’</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“‘I should certainly speak to the police,’</quote> I said.

<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘And be laughed at for my pains. Nothing of the sort.’</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“‘Then let me do so?’</quote>

<quote speaker ="joseph">“‘No, I forbid you. I won’t have a fuss made about such nonsense.’</quote>

“It was in vain to argue with <char gender ="male">him, for he was a very obstinate man</char>. <action char ="john">I
went about, however, with a heart which was full of forebodings</action>.

“On the third day after the coming of the letter <char gender ="male">my father</char> <action char ="joseph">went from
home to visit an old friend of his, Major Freebody, who is in command
of one of the forts upon Portsdown Hill</action>. I was glad that he should go,
for it seemed to me that he was farther from danger when he was away
from home. In that, however, I was in error. Upon the second day of his
absence I received a telegram from the major, imploring me to come at
once. <char gender ="male">My father</char> had fallen over one of the deep chalk-pits which abound
in the neighbourhood, and was lying senseless, with a shattered skull.
I hurried to him, but he passed away without having ever recovered his
consciousness. He had, as it appears, been returning from Fareham in
the twilight, and as the country was unknown to him, and the chalk-pit
unfenced, the jury had no hesitation in bringing in a verdict of ‘death
from accidental causes.’ Carefully as I examined every fact connected
with his death, I was unable to find anything which could suggest the
idea of murder. There were no signs of violence, no footmarks, no
robbery, no record of strangers having been seen upon the roads. And
yet I need not tell you that my mind was far from at ease, and that I
was well-nigh certain that some foul plot had been woven round him.

“In this sinister way I came into my inheritance. You will ask me why I
did not dispose of it? I answer, because <action char ="john">I was well convinced that our
troubles were in some way dependent upon an incident in my uncle’s
life, and that the danger would be as pressing in one house as in
another</action>.

“It was in January, ’85, that my poor father met his end, and two years
and eight months have elapsed since then. During that time I have lived
happily at Horsham, and I had begun to hope that this curse had passed
away from the family, and that it had ended with the last generation. I
had begun to take comfort too soon, however; yesterday morning the blow
fell in the very shape in which it had come upon my father.”</quote>

<action char ="john">The young man took from his waistcoat a crumpled envelope, and turning
to the table he shook out upon it five little dried orange pips.</action>

<quote speaker ="john">“This is the envelope,”</quote> he continued. <quote speaker ="joseph">“The postmark is London—eastern
division. Within are the very words which were upon <char gender ="male">my father’s</char> last
message: ‘K. K. K.’; and then ‘Put the papers on the sundial.’”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“What have you done?”</quote> asked <char gender ="male">Holmes</char>.

<quote speaker ="john">“Nothing.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Nothing?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“To tell the truth”</quote><action char ="john">—he sank his face into his thin, white hands</action>—<quote speaker ="john">“I have
felt helpless. I have felt like one of those poor rabbits when the
snake is writhing towards it. I seem to be in the grasp of some
resistless, inexorable evil, which no foresight and no precautions can
guard against.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Tut! tut!”</quote> cried <char gender ="male">Sherlock Holmes</char>. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“You must act, man, or you are lost.
Nothing but energy can save you. This is no time for despair.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“I have seen the police.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Ah!”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“But they listened to my story with a smile. I am convinced that the
inspector has formed the opinion that the letters are all practical
jokes, and that the deaths of my relations were really accidents, as
the jury stated, and were not to be connected with the warnings.”</quote>

<action char ="sherlock"><char gender ="male">Holmes</char> shook his clenched hands in the air</action>. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“Incredible imbecility!”</quote> <char gender ="male">he</char>
cried.

<quote speaker ="john">“They have, however, allowed me a <char gender = "male">policeman</char>, who may remain in the
house with me.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Has <char gender = "male">he</char> come with you to-night?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“No. <action char ="policeman"><char gender ="male">His</char> orders were to stay in the house</action>.”</quote>

<action char = "sherlock">Again <char gender ="male">Holmes</char> raved in the air.</action>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Why did you come to me?”</quote> <char gender ="male">he</char> said, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“and, above all, why did you not
come at once?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“I did not know. It was only to-day that I spoke to <char gender ="male">Major Prendergast</char>
about my troubles and was <action char ="major">advised by him to come to you</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“It is really two days since you had the letter. We should have acted
before this. You have no further evidence, I suppose, than that which
you have placed before us—no suggestive detail which might help us?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="john">“There is one thing,”</quote> said <char gender = "male">John Openshaw</char>. He rummaged in his coat
pocket, and, drawing out a piece of discoloured, blue-tinted paper, he
laid it out upon the table. <quote speaker ="john">“I have some remembrance,”</quote> said he, <quote speaker ="john">“that
on the day when <char gender = "male">my uncle</char> burned the papers I observed that the small,
unburned margins which lay amid the ashes were of this particular
colour. I found this single sheet upon the floor of his room, and I am
inclined to think that it may be one of the papers which has, perhaps,
fluttered out from among the others, and in that way has escaped
destruction. Beyond the mention of pips, I do not see that it helps us
much. I think myself that it is a page from some private diary. The
writing is undoubtedly my <char gender = "male">uncle’s</char>.”</quote>

<action char ="sherlock">Holmes moved the lamp</action>, and we both bent over the sheet of paper, which
showed by its ragged edge that it had indeed been torn from a book. It
was headed, “March, 1869,” and beneath were the following enigmatical
notices:

“4th. Hudson came. Same old platform.

“7th. Set the pips on McCauley, Paramore, and John Swain of St.
Augustine.

“9th. McCauley cleared.

“10th. John Swain cleared.

“12th. Visited Paramore. All well.”


<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Thank you!”</quote> said <char gender = "male">Holmes</char>, folding up the paper and returning it to our
visitor. <char gender = "male">“And now you must on no account lose another instant. We
cannot spare time even to discuss what you have told me. You must get
home instantly and act.”</char>

<quote speaker = "john">“What shall I do?”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“There is but one thing to do. It must be done at once. You must put
this piece of paper which you have shown us into the brass box which
you have described. You must also put in a note to say that all the
other papers were burned by your <char gender = "male">uncle</char>, and that this is the only one
which remains. You must assert that in such words as will carry
conviction with them. Having done this, you must at once put the box
out upon the sundial, as directed. Do you understand?”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“Entirely.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Do not think of revenge, or anything of the sort, at present. I think
that we may gain that by means of the law; but we have our web to
weave, while theirs is already woven. The first consideration is to
remove the pressing danger which threatens you. The second is to clear
up the mystery and to punish the guilty parties.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“I thank you,”</quote> said the <char gender = "male">young man</char>, rising and pulling on his overcoat.
<quote speaker = "john">“You have given me fresh life and hope. I shall certainly do as you
advise.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“Do not lose an instant. And, above all, take care of yourself in the
meanwhile, for I do not think that there can be a doubt that you are
threatened by a very real and imminent danger. How do you go back?”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“By train from Waterloo.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“It is not yet nine. The streets will be crowded, so I trust that you
may be in safety. And yet you cannot guard yourself too closely.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“<action char = "john">I am armed</action>.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“That is well. To-morrow I shall set to work upon your case.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“I shall see you at Horsham, then?”</quote>

<quote speaker = "sherlock">“No, your secret lies in London. It is there that I shall seek it.”</quote>

<quote speaker = "john">“<action char = "john">Then I shall call upon you in a day, or in two days, with news as to
the box and the papers. I shall take your advice in every particular</action>.”</quote>
He shook hands with us and took his leave. Outside the wind still
screamed and the rain splashed and pattered against the windows. This
strange, wild story seemed to have come to us from amid the mad
elements—blown in upon us like a sheet of sea-weed in a gale—and now to
have been reabsorbed by them once more.

<char gender ="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> sat for some time in silence, with his head sunk
forward and his eyes bent upon the red glow of the fire. Then he lit
his pipe, and leaning back in his chair he watched the blue smoke-rings
as they chased each other up to the ceiling.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“I think, <char gender ="male">Watson</char>,”</quote> he remarked at last, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“that of all our cases we have
had none more fantastic than this.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Save, perhaps, the Sign of Four.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Well, yes. Save, perhaps, that. And yet this <char gender ="male">John Openshaw</char> seems to me
to be walking amid even greater perils than did the Sholtos.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“But have you,”</quote> I asked, <quote speaker ="watson">“formed any definite conception as to what
these perils are?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“There can be no question as to their nature,”</quote> he answered.

<quote speaker ="watson">“Then what are they? Who is this K. K. K., and why does <action char ="npc_male">he pursue this
unhappy family?”</action></quote><!-- sorry I forgot our terminology to be used for unnamed characters-->


<action char ="sherlock"><char gender ="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> closed his eyes and placed his elbows upon the arms of
his chair, with his finger-tips together</action>. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“The ideal reasoner,”</quote> he
remarked, <char gender ="male">“would, when <char gender ="male">he</char> had once been shown a single fact in all its
bearings, deduce from it not only all the chain of events which led up
to it but also all the results which would follow from it. As Cuvier
could correctly describe a whole animal by the contemplation of a
single bone, so the observer who has thoroughly understood one link in
a series of incidents should be able to accurately state all the other
ones, both before and after. We have not yet grasped the results which
the reason alone can attain to. Problems may be solved in the study
which have baffled all those who have sought a solution by the aid of
their senses. To carry the art, however, to its highest pitch, it is
necessary that the reasoner should be able to utilise all the facts
which have come to his knowledge; and this in itself implies, as you
will readily see, a possession of all knowledge, which, even in these
days of free education and encyclopædias, is a somewhat rare
accomplishment. It is not so impossible, however, that a man should
possess all knowledge which is likely to be useful to him in his work,
and this I have endeavoured in my case to do. If I remember rightly,
you on one occasion, in the early days of our friendship, defined my
limits in a very precise fashion.”</char>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Yes,”</quote> I answered, laughing. <char gender ="male">“It was a singular document. Philosophy,
astronomy, and politics were marked at zero, I remember. Botany
variable, geology profound as regards the mud-stains from any region
within fifty miles of town, chemistry eccentric, anatomy unsystematic,
sensational literature and crime records unique, violin-player, boxer,
swordsman, lawyer, and self-poisoner by cocaine and tobacco. Those, I
think, were the main points of my analysis.”</char>

<char gender ="male">Holmes</char> grinned at the last item. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“Well,” he said, “I say now, as I said
then, that a <char gender ="male">man</char> should keep his little brain-attic stocked with all
the furniture that he is likely to use, and the rest he can put away in
the lumber-room of his library, where he can get it if he wants it.
Now, for such a case as the one which has been submitted to us
to-night, we need certainly to muster all our resources. Kindly hand me
down the letter K of the American Encyclopedia which stands upon the
shelf beside you. Thank you. Now let us consider the situation and see
what may be deduced from it. In the first place, we may start with a
strong presumption that <char gender ="male">Colonel Openshaw</char> had some very strong reason
for leaving America. Men at his time of life do not change all their
habits and exchange willingly the charming climate of Florida for the
lonely life of an English provincial town. His extreme love of solitude
in England suggests the idea that he was in fear of someone or
something, so we may assume as a working hypothesis that it was fear of
someone or something which drove him from America. As to what it was he
feared, we can only deduce that by considering the formidable letters
which were received by himself and his successors. Did you remark the
postmarks of those letters?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“The first was from Pondicherry, the second from Dundee, and the third
from London.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“From East London. What do you deduce from that?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“They are all seaports. That the writer was on board of a ship.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Excellent. We have already a clue. There can be no doubt that the
probability—the strong probability—is that the writer was on board of a
ship. And now let us consider another point. In the case of
Pondicherry, seven weeks elapsed between the threat and its fulfilment,
in Dundee it was only some three or four days. Does that suggest
anything?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“A greater distance to travel.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“But the letter had also a greater distance to come.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Then I do not see the point.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“There is at least a presumption that the vessel in which the <char gender ="male">man or
men</char> are is a sailing-ship. It looks as if they always send their
singular warning or token before them when starting upon their mission.
You see how quickly the deed followed the sign when it came from
Dundee. If they had come from Pondicherry in a steamer they would have
arrived almost as soon as their letter. But, as a matter of fact, seven
weeks elapsed. I think that those seven weeks represented the
difference between the mail-boat which brought the letter and the
sailing vessel which brought the writer.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“It is possible.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“More than that. It is probable. And now you see the deadly urgency of
this new case, and why <action char ="sherlock">I urged <char gender ="male">young Openshaw to caution</char></action>. The blow has
always fallen at the end of the time which it would take the senders to
travel the distance. But this one comes from London, and therefore we
cannot count upon delay.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Good God!” I cried. “What can it mean, this relentless persecution?”</quote>

 <quote speaker ="watson">“The papers which <char gender ="male">Openshaw</char> carried are obviously of vital importance to
the person or persons in the sailing-ship. I think that it is quite
clear that there must be more than one of them. <char gender ="male">A single man</char> could not
have carried out two deaths in such a way as to deceive a coroner’s
jury. There must have been several in it, and they must have been men
of resource and determination. Their papers they mean to have, be the
holder of them who it may. In this way you see K. K. K. ceases to be
the initials of an individual and becomes the badge of a society.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“But of what society?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Have you never—” said Sherlock Holmes, bending forward and sinking his
voice—“have you never heard of the Ku Klux Klan?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“I never have.”</quote>

<action char ="sherlock">Holmes turned over the leaves of the book upon his knee</action>. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“Here it is,”</quote>
said he presently:

“‘Ku Klux Klan. A name derived from the fanciful resemblance to the
sound produced by cocking a rifle. This terrible secret society was
formed by some ex-Confederate soldiers in the Southern states after the
Civil War, and it rapidly formed local branches in different parts of
the country, notably in Tennessee, Louisiana, the Carolinas, Georgia,
and Florida. Its power was used for political purposes, principally for
the terrorising of the negro voters and the murdering and driving from
the country of those who were opposed to its views. Its outrages were
usually preceded by a warning sent to the marked man in some fantastic
but generally recognised shape—a sprig of oak-leaves in some parts,
melon seeds or orange pips in others. On receiving this the victim
might either openly abjure his former ways, or might fly from the
country. If he braved the matter out, death would unfailingly come upon
him, and usually in some strange and unforeseen manner. So perfect was
the organisation of the society, and so systematic its methods, that
there is hardly a case upon record where any man succeeded in braving
it with impunity, or in which any of its outrages were traced home to
the perpetrators. For some years the organisation flourished in spite
of the efforts of the United States government and of the better
classes of the community in the South. Eventually, in the year 1869,
the movement rather suddenly collapsed, although there have been
sporadic outbreaks of the same sort since that date.’

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“You will observe,”</quote> said Holmes, laying down the volume, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“that the
sudden breaking up of the society was coincident with the disappearance
of <char gender ="male">Openshaw</char> from America with their papers. It may well have been cause
and effect. It is no wonder that <char gender ="male">he</char> and his family have some of the
more implacable spirits upon their track. You can understand that this
register and diary may implicate some of the first <char gender ="male">men</char> in the South,
and that there may be many who will not sleep easy at night until it is
recovered.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Then the page we have seen—”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Is such as we might expect. It ran, if I remember right, ‘sent the
pips to A, B, and C’—that is, sent the society’s warning to them. Then
there are successive entries that A and B cleared, or left the country,
and finally that C was visited, with, I fear, a sinister result for C.
Well, I think, Doctor, that we may let some light into this dark place,
and I believe that the only chance <char gender ="male">young Openshaw</char> has in the meantime
is to do what I have told <char gender ="male">him</char>. There is nothing more to be said or to
be done to-night, so hand me over my violin and let us try to forget
for half an hour the miserable weather and the still more miserable
ways of our fellow <char gender ="male">men</char>.”</quote>

It had cleared in the morning, and the sun was shining with a subdued
brightness through the dim veil which hangs over the great city.
<action char ="sherlock"><char gender ="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> was already at breakfast when I came down</action>.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“You will excuse me for not waiting for you,”</quote> said he; <char gender ="male">“I have, I
foresee, a very busy day before me in looking into this case of <char gender ="male">young
Openshaw’s</char>.”</char>

<quote speaker ="watson">“What steps will you take?”</quote> I asked.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“It will very much depend upon the results of my first inquiries. I may
have to go down to Horsham, after all.”</quote>

<char gender ="watson">“You will not go there first?”</char>

<char gender ="sherlock">“No, I shall commence with the City. Just ring the bell and the maid
will bring up your coffee.”</char>

<action char ="watson">As I waited, I lifted the unopened newspaper from the table and glanced
my eye over it. It rested upon a heading which sent a chill to my
heart.</action>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Holmes,”</quote> I cried, <quote speaker ="watson">“you are too late.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Ah!”</quote> said he, laying down his cup, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“I feared as much. How was it
done?”</quote> He spoke calmly, but I could see that he was deeply moved.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“<action char ="watson">My eye caught the name of <char gender ="male">Openshaw</char>, and the heading ‘Tragedy Near
Waterloo Bridge</action></quote>.’ Here is the account:

“‘Between nine and ten last night Police-Constable Cook, of the H
Division, on duty near Waterloo Bridge, heard a cry for help and a
splash in the water. The night, however, was extremely dark and stormy,
so that, in spite of the help of several passers-by, it was quite
impossible to effect a rescue. The alarm, however, was given, and, by
the aid of the water-police, the body was eventually recovered. It
proved to be that of a <char gender ="male">young gentleman</char> whose name, as it appears from
an envelope which was found in his pocket, was John Openshaw, and whose
residence is near Horsham. It is conjectured that <action char ="john">he may have been
hurrying down to catch the last train from Waterloo Station, and that
in his haste and the extreme darkness he missed his path and walked
over the edge of one of the small landing-places for river steamboats</action>.
The body exhibited no traces of violence, and there can be no doubt
that the deceased had been the victim of an unfortunate accident, which
should have the effect of calling the attention of the authorities to
the condition of the riverside landing-stages.’”


We sat in silence for some minutes, <char gender ="male">Holmes</char> more depressed and shaken
than I had ever seen him.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“That hurts my pride, <char gender ="male">Watson</char>,”</quote> he said at last. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“It is a petty feeling,
no doubt, but it hurts my pride. It becomes a personal matter with me
now, and, if God sends me health, I shall set my hand upon this gang.
That <char gender ="male">he</char> should come to me for help, and <action char ="sherlock">that I should send him away to
his death—</action>!”</quote> <action char ="sherlock">He sprang from his chair and paced about the room in
uncontrollable agitation, with a flush upon his sallow cheeks and a
nervous clasping and unclasping of his long thin hands</action>.


<quote speaker ="sherlock">“They must be cunning devils,”</quote> he exclaimed at last. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“How could they
have decoyed <char gender ="male">him</char> down there? The Embankment is not on the direct line
to the station. The bridge, no doubt, was too crowded, even on such a
night, for their purpose. Well, Watson, we shall see who will win in
the long run. I am going out now!”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“To the police?”</quote>

 
<action char ="sherlock">“No; <action char ="sherlock">I shall be my own police. When I have spun the web they may take
the flies, but not before</action>.”</action>

All day <action char ="watson">I was engaged in my professional work, and it was late in the
evening before I returned to Baker Street</action>. <char gender ="male">Sherlock Holmes</char> had not come
back yet. It was nearly ten o’clock before <action char ="sherlock">he entered, looking pale and
worn. He walked up to the sideboard, and tearing a piece from the loaf
he devoured it voraciously, washing it down with a long draught of
water</action>.


<quote speaker ="watson">“You are hungry,”</quote> I remarked.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Starving. It had escaped my memory. I have had nothing since
breakfast.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Nothing?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Not a bite. I had no time to think of it.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“And how have you succeeded?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Well.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“You have a clue?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“I have them in the hollow of my hand. <char gender ="male">Young Openshaw</char> shall not long
remain unavenged. Why, Watson, let us put their own devilish trade-mark
upon them. It is well thought of!”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“What do you mean?”</quote>


<action char ="sherlock">He took an orange from the cupboard, and tearing it to pieces he
squeezed out the pips upon the table. Of these he took five and thrust
them into an envelope. On the inside of the flap he wrote “S. H. for J.
O.” Then he sealed it and addressed it to “Captain James Calhoun,
Barque Lone Star, Savannah, Georgia.”</action>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“That will await him when he enters port,”</quote> said he, chuckling. <quote speaker ="sherlock">“It may
give him a sleepless night. He will find it as sure a precursor of <char gender ="male">his</char>
fate as Openshaw did before him.”</quote>


<quote speaker ="watson">“And who is this <char gender ="male">Captain Calhoun</char>?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“The leader of the gang. I shall have the others, but <char gender ="male">he</char> first.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“How did you trace it, then?”</quote>

<action char ="sherlock">He took a large sheet of paper from his pocket, all covered with dates
and names</action>.

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“I have spent the whole day,”</quote> said he, <quote speaker ="sherlock">“over Lloyd’s registers and
files of the old papers, following the future career of every vessel
which touched at Pondicherry in January and February in ’83. There were
thirty-six ships of fair tonnage which were reported there during those
months. Of these, one, the Lone Star, instantly attracted my
attention, since, although it was reported as having cleared from
London, the name is that which is given to one of the states of the
Union.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“Texas, I think.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“I was not and am not sure which; but I knew that the ship must have an
American origin.”</quote>

<quote speaker ="watson">“What then?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“I searched the Dundee records, and when I found that the barque Lone
Star was there in January, ’85, my suspicion became a certainty. I
then inquired as to the vessels which lay at present in the port of
London.”</quote>


<quote speaker ="watson">“Yes?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“The Lone Star had arrived here last week. I went down to the Albert
Dock and found that she had been taken down the river by the early tide
this morning, homeward bound to Savannah. I wired to Gravesend and
learned that she had passed some time ago, and as the wind is easterly
I have no doubt that she is now past the Goodwins and not very far from
the Isle of Wight.”</quote>


<quote speaker ="watson">“What will you do, then?”</quote>

<quote speaker ="sherlock">“Oh, I have my hand upon <char gender ="male">him</char>. He and the two mates, are as I learn, the
only native-born Americans in the ship. The others are Finns and
Germans. I know, also, that they were all three away from the ship last
night. I had it from the stevedore who has been loading their cargo. By
the time that their sailing-ship reaches Savannah the mail-boat will
have carried this letter, and the cable will have informed the police
of Savannah that these three gentlemen are badly wanted here upon a
charge of murder.”</quote>


There is ever a flaw, however, in the best laid of human plans, and the
murderers of <char gender ="male">John Openshaw</char> were never to receive the orange pips which
would show them that another, as cunning and as resolute as themselves,
was upon their track. Very long and very severe were the equinoctial
gales that year. We waited long for news of the Lone Star of
Savannah, but none ever reached us. We did at last hear that somewhere
far out in the Atlantic a shattered stern-post of a boat was seen
swinging in the trough of a wave, with the letters “L. S.” carved upon
it, and that is all which we shall ever know of the fate of the Lone
Star.

</story>
</passage>