<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../sherlock_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<passage number="8">

    <title>VIII. THE ADVENTURE OF THE SPECKLED BAND</title>

    <story>

        <p>On glancing over my notes of the seventy odd cases in which I have during the last eight
            years studied the methods of my friend <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Sherlock Holmes</char>, I find many tragic, some comic,
            a large number merely strange, but none commonplace; for, working as he did rather for
            the love of his art than for the acquirement of wealth, he refused to associate himself
            with any investigation which did not tend towards the unusual, and even the fantastic.
            Of all these varied cases, however, I cannot recall any which presented more singular
            features than that which was associated with the well-known Surrey family of the
            Roylotts of Stoke Moran. The events in question occurred in the early days of my
            association with Holmes, when we were sharing rooms as bachelors in Baker Street. It is
            possible that I might have placed them upon record before, but a promise of secrecy was
            made at the time, from which I have only been freed during the last month by the
            untimely death of the lady to whom the pledge was given. It is perhaps as well that the
            facts should now come to light, for I have reasons to know that there are widespread
            rumours as to the death of >Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char> which tend to make the matter even more
            terrible than the truth.</p>

        <p>It was early in April in the year '83 that <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> woke one morning</action> to find <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Sherlock Holmes</char>
            standing, fully dressed, by the side of my bed</action>. He was a late riser, as a rule, and as
            the clock on the mantelpiece showed me that it was only a quarter-past seven, <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> blinked
            up at him in some surprise, and perhaps just a little resentment, for I was myself
            regular in my habits</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Very sorry to knock you up, <char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">Watson</char>,</quote> said he,
                <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">but it's the common lot this morning. <char gender = "female" name = "mrsHudson">Mrs. Hudson</char>
                has been knocked up, she retorted upon me, and I on you.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">What is it, then—a fire?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No; a client. It seems that <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">a young lady</char> has arrived in
                a considerable state of excitement, who insists upon seeing me. She is waiting now
                in the sitting-room.</action> Now, when young ladies wander about the metropolis at this hour
                of the morning, and knock sleepy people up out of their beds, I presume that it is
                something very pressing which they have to communicate. Should it prove to be an
                interesting case, you would, I am sure, wish to follow it from the outset. I
                thought, at any rate, that I should call you and give you the chance.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">My dear fellow, I would not miss it for
            anything.</quote></p>

        <p>I had no keener pleasure than in following<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>in his professional investigations, and
            in admiring the rapid deductions, as swift as intuitions, and yet always founded on a
            logical basis with which he unravelled the problems which were submitted to him. <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char>
            rapidly threw on my clothes and was ready in a few minutes to accompany my friend down
            to the sitting-room.</action> <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">A lady dressed in black and heavily veiled</char>, who had been sitting in
            the window, rose as we entered.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Good-morning, madam,</quote> said<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>cheerily.
            <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">My name is <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Sherlock Holmes</char>. This is my intimate
                friend and associate, Dr.<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>, before whom you can speak as freely as before
                myself. Ha! I am glad to see that<char gender = "female" name = "mrsHudson"> Mrs. Hudson</char> has had the good sense to light the
                fire. Pray draw up to it, and I shall order you a cup of hot coffee, for I observe
                that <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">you</char> are shivering</action>.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">It is not cold which makes me shiver,</quote> said the
            woman in a low voice, <action>changing <char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">her</char> seat as requested</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">What, then?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">It is fear, Mr. <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>. It is terror.</quote> <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">She</char> raised
            her veil as she spoke</action>, and we could see that she was indeed in a pitiable state of
            agitation, her face all drawn and grey, with restless frightened eyes, like those of
            some hunted animal. Her features and figure were those of a woman of thirty, but her
            hair was shot with premature grey, and her expression was weary and haggard. <action>Sherlock
           <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>ran her over with one of his quick, all-comprehensive glances.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You must not fear,</quote> said <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> soothingly, bending
            forward and patting her forearm</action>. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">We shall soon set
                matters right, I have no doubt. You have come in by train this morning, I
                see.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">You know me, then?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, but I observe the second half of a return ticket in
                the palm of your left glove. You must have started early, and yet you had a good
                drive in a dog-cart, along heavy roads, before you reached the station.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">The lady</char> gave a violent start and stared in bewilderment at my companion</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There is no mystery, my dear madam,</quote> said he,
            smiling. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The left arm of your jacket is spattered with
                mud in no less than seven places. The marks are perfectly fresh. There is no vehicle
                save a dog-cart which throws up mud in that way, and then only when you sit on the
                left-hand side of the driver.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Whatever your reasons may be, you are perfectly
            correct,</quote> said she. <quote speaker="helenStoner"><action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> started from home before
                six, reached Leatherhead at twenty past, and came in by the first train to Waterloo</action>.
                Sir, I can stand this strain no longer; I shall go mad if it continues. I have no
                one to turn to—none, save only one, who cares for me, and he, poor fellow, can be of
                little aid. I have heard of you, Mr. <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>; I have heard of you from Mrs.
                <char gender = "female" name = "mrsFarintosh">Farintosh</char>, whom you helped in the hour of her sore need. It was from her that I had
                your address. Oh, sir, do you not think that you could help me, too, and at least
                throw a little light through the dense darkness which surrounds me? At present it is
                out of my power to reward you for your services, but in a month or six weeks I shall
                be married, with the control of my own income, and then at least you shall not find
                me ungrateful.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> turned to his desk and, unlocking it, drew out a small case-book, which he
            consulted.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"><char gender = "female" name = "mrsFarintosh">Farintosh</char>,</quote> said he. <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">Ah yes, I recall the case; it was concerned with an opal
                tiara. I think it was before your time,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>. I can only say, madam, that I shall
                be happy to devote the same care to your case as I did to that of your friend. As to
                reward, my profession is its own reward; but you are at liberty to defray whatever
                expenses I may be put to, at the time which suits you best. And now I beg that you
                will lay before us everything that may help us in forming an opinion upon the
                matter.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Alas!</quote> replied our visitor, <quote
                speaker="helenStoner">the very horror of my situation lies in the fact that my
                fears are so vague, and my suspicions depend so entirely upon small points, which
                might seem trivial to another, that even he to whom of all others I have a right to
                look for help and advice looks upon all that I tell him about it as the fancies of a
                nervous woman. He does not say so, but I can read it from his soothing answers and
                averted eyes. But I have heard, Mr. <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, that you can see deeply into the
                manifold wickedness of the human heart. You may advise me how to walk amid the
                dangers which encompass me.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I am all attention, madam.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">My name is<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Helen Stoner</char>, and I am living with my
                stepfather, who is the last survivor of one of the oldest Saxon families in England,
                the Roylotts of Stoke Moran, on the western border of Surrey.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> nodded his head</action>. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The name is familiar to
                me,</quote> said he.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">The family was at one time among the richest in England,
                and the estates extended over the borders into Berkshire in the north, and Hampshire
                in the west. In the last century, however, four successive heirs were of a dissolute
                and wasteful disposition, and the family ruin was eventually completed by a gambler
                in the days of the Regency. Nothing was left save a few acres of ground, and the
                two-hundred-year-old house, which is itself crushed under a heavy mortgage. The last
                squire dragged out his existence there, living the horrible life of an aristocratic
                pauper; but his only son, my stepfather, seeing that he must adapt himself to the
                new conditions, obtained an advance from a relative, which enabled him to take a
                medical degree and went out to Calcutta, where, by his professional skill and his
                force of character, he established a large practice. In a fit of anger, however,
                caused by some robberies which had been perpetrated in the house, he beat his native
                butler to death and narrowly escaped a capital sentence. As it was, he suffered a
                long term of imprisonment and afterwards returned to England a morose and
                disappointed man.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner"><action>When Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "sgrimesbyRoylott">Roylott</char> was in India he married my mother,</action> <char gender = "female" name = "mrsStoner">Mrs.
                Stoner</char>, the young widow of Major-General Stoner, of the Bengal Artillery. My sister
                <char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">Julia</char> and I were twins, and we were only two years old at the time of my mother's
            re-marriage. <action><char gender = "female" name = "mrsStoner">She</char> had a considerable sum of money—not less than £ 1000 a year—and
                this she bequeathed to Dr.</action> <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Roylott</char> entirely while we resided with him, with a
                provision that a certain annual sum should be allowed to each of us in the event of
                our marriage. Shortly after our return to England <action><char gender = "female" name = "mrsStoner">my mother</char> died—she was killed
                eight years ago in a railway accident near Crewe.</action> <action>Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Roylott</char> then abandoned his
                attempts to establish himself in practice in London and took us to live with him in
                the old ancestral house at Stoke Moran.</action> The money which my mother had left was
                enough for all our wants, and there seemed to be no obstacle to our
                happiness.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">But a terrible change came over our stepfather about this
                time. Instead of making friends and exchanging visits with our neighbours, who had
                at first been overjoyed to see a Roylott of Stoke Moran back in the old family seat,
            <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> shut himself up in his house and seldom came out save to indulge in ferocious
                quarrels with whoever might cross his path</action>. Violence of temper approaching to mania
                has been hereditary in the men of the family, and in my stepfather's case it had, I
                believe, been intensified by his long residence in the tropics. A series of
                disgraceful brawls took place, two of which ended in the police-court, until at last
                he became the terror of the village, and the folks would fly at his approach, for he
                is a man of immense strength, and absolutely uncontrollable in his
            anger.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Last week <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> hurled the local blacksmith over a parapet
                into a stream</action>, and it was only by paying over all the money which I could gather
                together that I was able to avert another public exposure. He had no friends at all
                save the wandering gipsies, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> would give these vagabonds leave to encamp upon
                the few acres of bramble-covered land which represent the family estate, and would
                accept in return the hospitality of their tents, wandering away with them sometimes
                for weeks on end</action>. He has a passion also for Indian animals, which are sent over to
                him by a correspondent, and he has at this moment a cheetah and a baboon, which
                wander freely over his grounds and are feared by the villagers almost as much as
                their master.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">You can imagine from what I say that my poor sister <char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">Julia</char>
                and I had no great pleasure in our lives. No servant would stay with us, and for a
                long time we did all the work of the house. She was but thirty at the time of her
                death, and yet her hair had already begun to whiten, even as mine has.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your sister is dead, then?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner"><action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">She</char> died just two years ago</action>, and it is of her death that I
                wish to speak to you. You can understand that, living the life which I have
                described, we were little likely to see anyone of our own age and position. We had,
                however, an aunt, my mother's maiden sister, Miss <char gender = "female" name = "honoriaWestphail">Honoria Westphail</char>, who lives near
                Harrow, and we were occasionally allowed to pay short visits at this lady's house.
                <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">Julia</char> went there at Christmas two years ago, and met there a half-pay major of
                marines, to whom she became engaged</action>. My stepfather learned of the engagement when my
                sister returned and offered no objection to the marriage; but within a fortnight of
                the day which had been fixed for the wedding, the terrible event occurred which has
                deprived me of my only companion.</quote></p>

        <p><action>Sherlock<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>had been leaning back in his chair with his eyes closed and his head sunk
            in a cushion, but he half opened his lids now and glanced across at his visitor.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Pray be precise as to details,</quote> said he.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">It is easy for me to be so, for every event of that
                dreadful time is seared into my memory. The manor-house is, as I have already said,
                very old, and only one wing is now inhabited. The bedrooms in this wing are on the
                ground floor, the sitting-rooms being in the central block of the buildings. Of
                these bedrooms the first is <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char>'s, the second my sister's, and the third my
                own. There is no communication between them, but they all open out into the same
                corridor. Do I make myself plain?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Perfectly so.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">The windows of the three rooms open out upon the lawn. That
                fatal night <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char> had gone to his room early</action>, though we knew that he had not
                retired to rest, for my sister was troubled by the smell of the strong Indian cigars
                which it was his custom to smoke. <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">She left her room</char>, therefore, and came into mine,
                where she sat for some time, chatting about her approaching wedding</action>. At eleven
            o'clock <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">she</char> rose to leave me, but she paused at the door and looked
            back</action>.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner"><subq speaker="juliaStoner">Tell me, <char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">Helen</char>,</subq> said
                she, <subq speaker="juliaStoner">have you ever heard anyone whistle in the dead of
                    the night?</subq>
                <subq speaker="helenStoner">Never,</subq> said I. <subq speaker="helenStoner">I
                    suppose that you could not possibly whistle, yourself, in your sleep?</subq>
                <subq speaker="juliaStoner">Certainly not.</subq>
                <subq speaker="helenStoner">But why?</subq>
                <subq speaker="juliaStoner">Because during the last few nights I have always, about
                    three in the morning, heard a low, clear whistle. I am a light sleeper, and it
                    has awakened me. I cannot tell where it came from—perhaps from the next room,
                    perhaps from the lawn. I thought that I would just ask you whether you had heard
                    it.</subq>
                <subq speaker="helenStoner">No, I have not. It must be those wretched gipsies in
                    the plantation.</subq>
                <subq speaker="juliaStoner">Very likely. And yet if it were on the lawn, I wonder
                    that you did not hear it also.</subq>
                <subq speaker="helenStoner">Ah, but I sleep more heavily than you.</subq>
                <subq speaker="juliaStoner">Well, it is of no great consequence, at any
                    rate.</subq> <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">She</char> smiled back at me, closed my door, and a few moments later I
                heard her key turn in the lock</action>.'</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Indeed,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>. <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">Was it your custom always to lock yourselves in at
                night?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Always.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And why?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I think that I mentioned to you that the <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Doctor</char> kept a
                cheetah and a baboon. We had no feeling of security unless our doors were
                locked.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Quite so. Pray proceed with your statement.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I could not sleep that night. A vague feeling of impending
                misfortune impressed me. My sister and I, you will recollect, were twins, and you
                know how subtle are the links which bind two souls which are so closely allied. It
                was a wild night. The wind was howling outside, and the rain was beating and
                splashing against the windows. Suddenly, amid all the hubbub of the gale, there
                burst forth the wild scream of a terrified woman. I knew that it was my sister's
                voice. <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> sprang from my bed, wrapped a shawl round me, and rushed into the corridor</action>.
            <action> As <char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> opened my door I seemed to hear a low whistle, such as my sister described, and
                a few moments later a clanging sound, as if a mass of metal had fallen</action>. As <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> ran
                down the passage,</action> my sister's door was unlocked, and revolved slowly upon its
            hinges. <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> stared at it horror-stricken, not knowing what was about to issue from it.</action>
            By the light of the corridor-lamp I saw my sister appear at the opening, <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">her</char> face
                blanched with terror, her hands groping for help, her whole figure swaying to and
                fro like that of a drunkard.</action> <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> ran to her and threw my arms round her</action>, but at that
            moment <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">her</char> knees seemed to give way and she fell to the ground. She writhed as one
                who is in terrible pain, and her limbs were dreadfully convulsed</action>. At first I thought
            that she had not recognised me, but as <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> bent over her</action> <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">she</char> suddenly shrieked out in
                a voice which I shall never forget</action>, 'Oh, my God! <char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">Helen</char>! It was the band! The
            speckled band!' There was something else which she would fain have said, and <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">she</char>
                stabbed with her finger into the air</action> in the direction of the<char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott"> Doctor</char>'s room, but a
            fresh convulsion seized her and choked her words. <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> rushed out, calling loudly for
                my stepfather, and I met him hastening from his room in his dressing-gown</action>. When he
            reached my sister's side she was unconscious, and though <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> poured brandy down her
                throat and sent for medical aid from the village</action>, all efforts were in vain, for <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">she</char>
                slowly sank and died without having recovered her consciousness</action>. Such was the
                dreadful end of my beloved sister.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">One moment,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">are you sure about this whistle and metallic sound? Could
                you swear to it?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">That was what the county coroner asked me at the inquiry.
                It is my strong impression that I heard it, and yet, among the crash of the gale and
                the creaking of an old house, I may possibly have been deceived.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Was your sister dressed?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">No, she was in her night-dress. In her right hand was found
                the charred stump of a match, and in her left a match-box.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Showing that <action><char gender = "female" name = "juliaStoner">she</char> had struck a light and looked about her
                when the alarm took place</action>. That is important. And what conclusions did the coroner
                come to?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">He investigated the case with great care, for <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char>'s
                conduct had long been notorious in the county, but he was unable to find any
                satisfactory cause of death. My evidence showed that the door had been fastened upon
                the inner side, and the windows were blocked by old-fashioned shutters with broad
                iron bars, which were secured every night. The walls were carefully sounded, and
                were shown to be quite solid all round, and the flooring was also thoroughly
                examined, with the same result. The chimney is wide, but is barred up by four large
                staples. It is certain, therefore, that my sister was quite alone when she met her
                end. Besides, there were no marks of any violence upon her.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">How about poison?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">The doctors examined her for it, but without
                success.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">What do you think that this unfortunate lady died of,
                then?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">It is my belief that she died of pure fear and nervous
                shock, though what it was that frightened her I cannot imagine.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Were there gipsies in the plantation at the
                time?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, there are nearly always some there.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Ah, and what did you gather from this allusion to a
                band—a speckled band?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Sometimes I have thought that it was merely the wild talk
                of delirium, sometimes that it may have referred to some band of people, perhaps to
                these very gipsies in the plantation. I do not know whether the spotted
                handkerchiefs which so many of them wear over their heads might have suggested the
                strange adjective which she used.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> shook his head like a man who is far from being satisfied</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">These are very deep waters,</quote> said he; <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">pray go on with your narrative.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Two years have passed since then, and my life has been
            until lately lonelier than ever. A month ago, however, <action><char gender = "male" name = "percyArmitage">a dear friend</char>, whom I have
                known for many years, has done me the honour to ask my hand in marriage</action>. His name is
                Armitage—<char gender = "male" name = "percyArmitage">Percy Armitage</char>—the second son of Mr. Armitage, of Crane Water, near
                Reading. My stepfather has offered no opposition to the match, and we are to be
                married in the course of the spring. Two days ago some repairs were started in the
                west wing of the building, and my bedroom wall has been pierced, so that I have had
                to move into the chamber in which my sister died, and to sleep in the very bed in
                which she slept. Imagine, then, my thrill of terror when last night, as I lay awake,
                thinking over her terrible fate, <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> suddenly heard in the silence of the night the
                    low whistle which had been the herald of her own death</action>. <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> sprang up and lit the
                lamp, but nothing was to be seen in the room</action>. I was too shaken to go to bed again,
            however, so <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">I</char> dressed, and as soon as it was daylight I slipped down, got a dog-cart
                at the Crown Inn, which is opposite, and drove to Leatherhead</action>, from whence I have
                come on this morning with the one object of seeing you and asking your
                advice.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You have done wisely,</quote> said my friend. <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">But have you told me all?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, all.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes"><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">Miss Roylott</char>, you have not. You are screening your
                stepfather.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Why, what do you mean?</quote></p>

        <p>For answer<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>pushed back the frill of black lace which fringed the hand that lay
            upon our visitor's knee</action>. Five little livid spots, the marks of four fingers and a thumb,
            were printed upon the white wrist.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You have been cruelly used,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>.</p>

        <p><action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">The lady</char> coloured deeply and covered over her injured wrist</action>. <quote
                speaker="helenStoner">He is a hard man,</quote> she said, <quote
                speaker="helenStoner">and perhaps he hardly knows his own strength.</quote></p>

        <p>There was a long silence, during which<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>leaned his chin upon his hands and stared
            into the crackling fire.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">This is a very deep business,</quote> he said at last.
                <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There are a thousand details which I should desire
                to know before I decide upon our course of action. Yet we have not a moment to lose.
                If we were to come to Stoke Moran to-day, would it be possible for us to see over
                these rooms without the knowledge of your stepfather?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">As it happens, <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> spoke of coming into town to-day upon
                some most important business.</action> It is probable that he will be away all day, and that
                there would be nothing to disturb you. We have a housekeeper now, but she is old and
                foolish, and I could easily get her out of the way.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Excellent. You are not averse to this trip,
               <char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">By no means.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Then we shall both come. What are you going to do
                yourself?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I have one or two things which I would wish to do now that
                I am in town. But I shall return by the twelve o'clock train, so as to be there in
                time for your coming.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And you may expect us early in the afternoon. I have
                myself some small business matters to attend to. Will you not wait and
                breakfast?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">No, I must go. My heart is lightened already since I have
                confided my trouble to you. I shall look forward to seeing you again this
                afternoon.</quote> <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">She</char> dropped her thick black veil over her face and glided from
            the room.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And what do you think of it all,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>?</quote> asked
            <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Sherlock Holmes</char>, leaning back in his chair.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">It seems to me to be a most dark and sinister
                business.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Dark enough and sinister enough.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Yet if the lady is correct in saying that the flooring and
                walls are sound, and that the door, window, and chimney are impassable, then her
                sister must have been undoubtedly alone when she met her mysterious end.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">What becomes, then, of these nocturnal whistles, and
                what of the very peculiar words of the dying woman?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">I cannot think.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">When you combine the ideas of whistles at night, the
                presence of a band of gipsies who are on intimate terms with this old doctor, the
                fact that we have every reason to believe that the doctor has an interest in
                preventing his stepdaughter's marriage, the dying allusion to a band, and, finally,
                the fact that <action>Miss<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Helen Stoner</char> heard a metallic clang</action>, which might have been caused
                by one of those metal bars that secured the shutters falling back into its place, I
                think that there is good ground to think that the mystery may be cleared along those
                lines.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">But what, then, did the gipsies do?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I cannot imagine.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">I see many objections to any such theory.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And so do I. It is precisely for that reason that we are
                going to Stoke Moran this day. I want to see whether the objections are fatal, or if
                they may be explained away. But what in the name of the devil!</quote></p>

        <p>The ejaculation had been drawn from my companion by the fact that our door had been
            suddenly dashed open, and that <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">a huge man</char> had framed himself in the aperture</action>. His
            costume was a peculiar mixture of the professional and of the agricultural, having a
            black top-hat, a long frock-coat, and a pair of high gaiters, with a hunting-crop
            swinging in his hand. So tall was he that his hat actually brushed the cross bar of the
            doorway, and his breadth seemed to span it across from side to side. A large face,
            seared with a thousand wrinkles, burned yellow with the sun, and marked with every evil
            passion, was turned from one to the other of us, while his deep-set, bile-shot eyes, and
            his high, thin, fleshless nose, gave him somewhat the resemblance to a fierce old bird
            of prey.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">Which of you is <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>?</quote> asked this
            apparition.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">My name, sir; but you have the advantage of me,</quote>
            said my companion quietly.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">I am Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char>, of Stoke Moran.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Indeed,<char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott"> Doctor</char>,</quote> said<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>blandly. <quote
                speaker="sherlockHolmes">Pray take a seat.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">I will do nothing of the kind. My stepdaughter has been
                here. I have traced her. What has she been saying to you?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is a little cold for the time of the year,</quote>
            said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">What has she been saying to you?</quote> screamed the
            old man furiously.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">But I have heard that the crocuses promise well,</quote>
            continued my companion imperturbably.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">Ha! You put me off, do you?</quote> said our new
            visitor, taking a step forward and shaking his hunting-crop. <quote
                speaker="grimesbyRoylott">I know you, you scoundrel! I have heard of you before.
                You are Holmes, the meddler.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">My friend</char> smiled</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott"><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, the busybody!</quote></p>

        <p>His smile broadened.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott"><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, the Scotland Yard Jack-in-office!</quote></p>

        <p><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> chuckled heartily. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your conversation is most entertaining,</quote> said he.
            <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">When you go out close the door, for there is a decided draught.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">I will go when I have had my say. Don't you dare to
            meddle with my affairs. I know that<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> has been here. <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">I</char> traced her!</action> I am a
            dangerous man to fall foul of! See here.</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">He</char> stepped swiftly forward, seized
            the poker, and bent it into a curve with his huge brown hands</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="grimesbyRoylott">See that you keep yourself out of my grip,</quote> he
            snarled, and <action>hurling the twisted poker into the fireplace <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char> strode out of the room</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">He seems a very amiable person,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>,
            laughing. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I am not quite so bulky, but if he had
                remained I might have shown him that my grip was not much more feeble than his
                own.</quote> <action>As <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> spoke he picked up the steel poker and, with a sudden effort,
            straightened it out again</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Fancy his having the insolence to confound me with the
                official detective force! This incident gives zest to our investigation, however,
                and I only trust that our little friend will not suffer from her imprudence in
                allowing this brute to trace her. And now,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>, we shall order breakfast, and
                afterwards I shall walk down to Doctors' Commons, where I hope to get some data
                which may help us in this matter.</quote></p>

        <p>It was nearly one o'clock when <action>Sherlock<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>returned from his excursion. He held in
            his hand a sheet of blue paper, scrawled over with notes and figures</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I have seen the will of the deceased wife,</quote> said
            he. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">To determine its exact meaning I have been obliged
                to work out the present prices of the investments with which it is concerned. The
                total income, which at the time of the wife's death was little short of £ 1,100, is
                now, through the fall in agricultural prices, not more than £ 750. Each daughter can
                claim an income of £ 250, in case of marriage. It is evident, therefore, that if
                both girls had married, this beauty would have had a mere pittance, while even one
                of them would cripple him to a very serious extent. My morning's work has not been
                wasted, since it has proved that he has the very strongest motives for standing in
                the way of anything of the sort. And now,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>, this is too serious for dawdling,
                especially as the old man is aware that we are interesting ourselves in his affairs;
                so if you are ready, we shall call a cab and drive to Waterloo. I should be very
                much obliged if you would slip your revolver into your pocket. An Eley's No. 2 is an
                excellent argument with gentlemen who can twist steel pokers into knots. That and a
                tooth-brush are, I think, all that we need.</quote></p>

        <p>At Waterloo we were fortunate in catching a train for Leatherhead, where we hired a trap
            at the station inn and drove for four or five miles through the lovely Surrey lanes. It
            was a perfect day, with a bright sun and a few fleecy clouds in the heavens. The trees
            and wayside hedges were just throwing out their first green shoots, and the air was full
            of the pleasant smell of the moist earth. To me at least there was a strange contrast
            between the sweet promise of the spring and this sinister quest upon which we were
            engaged. <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">My companion</char> sat in the front of the trap, his arms folded, his hat pulled down
            over his eyes, and his chin sunk upon his breast, buried in the deepest thought.</action>
            Suddenly, however, <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> started, tapped me on the shoulder, and pointed over the
            meadows.</action></p>

        <p><quote  speaker="sherlockHolmes">Look there!</quote> said he.</p>

        <p>A heavily timbered park stretched up in a gentle slope, thickening into a grove at the
            highest point. From amid the branches there jutted out the grey gables and high
            roof-tree of a very old mansion.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Stoke Moran?</quote> said he.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="unnamedDriver">Yes, sir, that be the house of Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char>,</quote> remarked the
            driver.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There is some building going on there,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>; <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">that is where
                we are going.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="unnamedDriver">There's the village,</quote> said the driver, pointing to a cluster of roofs some
            distance to the left; <quote speaker="unnamedDriver">but if you want to get to the house, you'll find it shorter
                to get over this stile, and so by the footpath over the fields. There it is, where
                the lady is walking.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And the lady, I fancy, is<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>,</quote> observed <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, shading his eyes.</action>
            <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Yes, I think we had better do as you suggest.</quote></p>

        <p>We got off, paid our fare, and the trap rattled back on its way to Leatherhead.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I thought it as well,</quote> said<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>as we climbed the stile, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">that
                this fellow should think we had come here as architects, or on some definite
                business. It may stop his gossip. Good-afternoon,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>. You see that we have
                been as good as our word.</quote></p>

        <p>Our client of the morning had hurried forward to meet us with a face which spoke her joy.
            <quote speaker="helenStoner">I have been waiting so eagerly for you,</quote> <action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">she</char> cried, shaking hands with
            us warmly</action>. <quote speaker="helenStoner">All has turned out splendidly. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char> has gone to town, and it is
                unlikely that he will be back before evening.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">We have had the pleasure of making the<char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott"> Doctor</char>'s acquaintance,</quote> said <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>,
            and in a few words he sketched out what had occurred.<action><char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> turned white to the
            lips as she listened</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Good heavens!</quote> she cried, <quote speaker="helenStoner">he has followed me, then.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">So it appears.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">He is so cunning that I never know when I am safe from him. What will he say when
                he returns?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">He must guard himself, for he may find that there is someone more cunning than
                himself upon his track. You must lock yourself up from him to-night. If he is
                violent, we shall take you away to your aunt's at Harrow. Now, we must make the best
                use of our time, so kindly take us at once to the rooms which we are to
                examine.</quote></p>

        <p>The building was of grey, lichen-blotched stone, with a high central portion and two
            curving wings, like the claws of a crab, thrown out on each side. In one of these wings
            the windows were broken and blocked with wooden boards, while the roof was partly caved
            in, a picture of ruin. The central portion was in little better repair, but the
            right-hand block was comparatively modern, and the blinds in the windows, with the blue
            smoke curling up from the chimneys, showed that this was where the family resided. Some
            scaffolding had been erected against the end wall, and the stone-work had been broken
            into, but there were no signs of any workmen at the moment of our visit.<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>walked
            slowly up and down the ill-trimmed lawn and examined with deep attention the outsides of
            the windows.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">This, I take it, belongs to the room in which you used to sleep, the centre one to
                your sister's, and the one next to the main building to <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char>'s
                chamber?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Exactly so. But I am now sleeping in the middle one.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Pending the alterations, as I understand. By the way, there does not seem to be
                any very pressing need for repairs at that end wall.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">There were none. I believe that it was an excuse to move me from my
            room.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Ah! that is suggestive. Now, on the other side of this narrow wing runs the
                corridor from which these three rooms open. There are windows in it, of
                course?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, but very small ones. Too narrow for anyone to pass through.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">As you both locked your doors at night, your rooms were unapproachable from that
                side. Now, would you have the kindness to go into your room and bar your
                shutters?</quote></p>

        <p>,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">Miss Stoner</char> did so, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, after a careful examination through the open window,
            endeavoured in every way to force the shutter open, but without success</action>. There was no
            slit through which a knife could be passed to raise the bar. Then with his lens <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char>
            tested the hinges</action>, but they were of solid iron, built firmly into the massive masonry.
            <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Hum!</quote> said he, <action>scratching <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">his</char> chin in some perplexity</action>, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">my
                theory certainly presents some difficulties. No one could pass these shutters if
                they were bolted. Well, we shall see if the inside throws any light upon the
                matter.</quote></p>

        <p>A small side door led into the whitewashed corridor from which the three bedrooms opened.
           <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>refused to examine the third chamber</action>, so we passed at once to the second, that in
            which<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> was now sleeping, and in which her sister had met with her fate. It
            was a homely little room, with a low ceiling and a gaping fireplace, after the fashion
            of old country-houses. A brown chest of drawers stood in one corner, a narrow
            white-counterpaned bed in another, and a dressing-table on the left-hand side of the
            window. These articles, with two small wicker-work chairs, made up all the furniture in
            the room save for a square of Wilton carpet in the centre. The boards round and the
            panelling of the walls were of brown, worm-eaten oak, so old and discoloured that it may
            have dated from the original building of the house.<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>drew one of the chairs into a
            corner and sat silent, while his eyes travelled round and round and up and down, taking
            in every detail of the apartment.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Where does that bell communicate with?</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> asked at last pointing to a
            thick bell-rope which hung down beside the bed</action>, the tassel actually lying upon the
            pillow.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">It goes to the housekeeper's room.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It looks newer than the other things?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, it was only put there a couple of years ago.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your sister asked for it, I suppose?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">No, I never heard of her using it. We used always to get what we wanted for
                ourselves.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Indeed, it seemed unnecessary to put so nice a bell-pull there. You will excuse me
            for a few minutes while I satisfy myself as to this floor.</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> threw himself
            down upon his face with his lens in his hand and crawled swiftly backward and forward,
            examining minutely the cracks between the boards. Then he did the same with the
            wood-work with which the chamber was panelled. </action>Finally <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> walked over to the bed and
            spent some time in staring at it and in running his eye up and down the wall. Finally he
            took the bell-rope in his hand and gave it a brisk tug</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Why, it's a dummy,</quote> said he.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Won't it ring?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, it is not even attached to a wire. This is very interesting. You can see now
                that it is fastened to a hook just above where the little opening for the ventilator
                is.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">How very absurd! I never noticed that before.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Very strange!</quote> muttered <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char>, pulling at the rope</action>. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There are one
                or two very singular points about this room. For example, what a fool a builder must
                be to open a ventilator into another room, when, with the same trouble, he might
                have communicated with the outside air!</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">That is also quite modern,</quote> said the lady.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Done about the same time as the bell-rope?</quote> remarked Holmes.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, there were several little changes carried out about that time.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">They seem to have been of a most interesting character—dummy bell-ropes, and
                ventilators which do not ventilate. With your permission,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>, we shall now
                carry our researches into the inner apartment.</quote></p>

        <p>Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char>'s chamber was larger than that of his step-daughter, but was as
            plainly furnished. A camp-bed, a small wooden shelf full of books, mostly of a technical
            character, an armchair beside the bed, a plain wooden chair against the wall, a round
            table, and a large iron safe were the principal things which met the eye.<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>walked
            slowly round and examined each and all of them with the keenest interest.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">What's in here?</quote> he asked, tapping the safe.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">My stepfather's business papers.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Oh! you have seen inside, then?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Only once, some years ago. I remember that it was full of papers.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">There isn't a cat in it, for example?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">No. What a strange idea!</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Well, look at this!</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> took up a small saucer of milk which stood on the
            top of it.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">No; we don't keep a cat. But there is a cheetah and a baboon.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Ah, yes, of course! Well, a cheetah is just a big cat, and yet a saucer of milk
                does not go very far in satisfying its wants, I daresay. There is one point which I
                should wish to determine.</quote> <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">He</char> squatted down in front of the wooden chair and
            examined the seat of it with the greatest attention</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Thank you. That is quite settled,</quote> said he, <action>rising and putting <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">his</char> lens in
            his pocket</action>. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Hullo! Here is something interesting!</quote></p>

        <p>The object which had caught his eye was a small dog lash hung on one corner of the bed.
            The lash, however, was curled upon itself and tied so as to make a loop of whipcord.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">What do you make of that,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">It's a common enough lash. But I don't know why it should be tied.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">That is not quite so common, is it? Ah, me! it's a wicked world, and when a clever
                man turns his brains to crime it is the worst of all. I think that I have seen
                enough now,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>, and with your permission we shall walk out upon the
                lawn.</quote></p>

        <p>I had never seen my friend's face so grim or his brow so dark as it was when we turned
            from the scene of this investigation. We had walked several times up and down the lawn,
            neither<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> nor myself liking to break in upon his thoughts before he roused
            himself from his reverie.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is very essential,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>,</quote> said he, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">that you should
                absolutely follow my advice in every respect.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I shall most certainly do so.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The matter is too serious for any hesitation. Your life may depend upon your
                compliance.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I assure you that I am in your hands.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">In the first place, both my friend and I must spend the night in your
                room.</quote></p>

        <p>Both<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> and I gazed at him in astonishment.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Yes, it must be so. Let me explain. I believe that that is the village inn over
                there?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Yes, that is the Crown.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Very good. Your windows would be visible from there?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Certainly.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You must confine yourself to your room, on pretence of a headache, when your
                stepfather comes back. Then when you hear him retire for the night, you must open
                the shutters of your window, undo the hasp, put your lamp there as a signal to us,
                and then withdraw quietly with everything which you are likely to want into the room
                which you used to occupy. I have no doubt that, in spite of the repairs, you could
                manage there for one night.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Oh, yes, easily.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The rest you will leave in our hands.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">But what will you do?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">We shall spend the night in your room, and we shall investigate the cause of this
                noise which has disturbed you.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">I believe, Mr. <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, that you have already made up your mind,</quote> said <char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner">Miss
            Stoner</char>, laying her hand upon my companion's sleeve.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Perhaps I have.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">Then, for pity's sake, tell me what was the cause of my sister's
            death.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I should prefer to have clearer proofs before I speak.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="helenStoner">You can at least tell me whether my own thought is correct, and if she died from
                some sudden fright.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, I do not think so. I think that there was probably some more tangible cause.
                And now,<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char>, we must leave you for if <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char> returned and saw us our
                journey would be in vain. Good-bye, and be brave, for if you will do what I have
                told you, you may rest assured that we shall soon drive away the dangers that
                threaten you.</quote></p>

        <p>Sherlock<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>and I had no difficulty in engaging a bedroom and sitting-room at the
            Crown Inn. They were on the upper floor, and from our window we could command a view of
            the avenue gate, and of the inhabited wing of Stoke Moran Manor House. At dusk we saw
            <action>Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char> drive past, his huge form looming up beside the little figure of
            the lad who drove him</action>. The boy had some slight difficulty in undoing the heavy iron
            gates, and we heard the hoarse roar of the<char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott"> Doctor</char>'s voice and saw the fury with which <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">he</char>
            shook his clinched fists at him</action>. The trap drove on, and a few minutes later we saw a
            sudden light spring up among the trees as the lamp was lit in one of the
            sitting-rooms.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do you know,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>,</quote> said<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>as we sat together in the gathering
            darkness, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I have really some scruples as to taking you to-night. There is a
                distinct element of danger.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Can I be of assistance?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Your presence might be invaluable.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Then I shall certainly come.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is very kind of you.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">You speak of danger. You have evidently seen more in these rooms than was visible
                to me.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">No, but I fancy that I may have deduced a little more. I imagine that you saw all
                that I did.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">I saw nothing remarkable save the bell-rope, and what purpose that could answer I
                confess is more than I can imagine.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You saw the ventilator, too?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Yes, but I do not think that it is such a very unusual thing to have a small
                opening between two rooms. It was so small that a rat could hardly pass
                through.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I knew that we should find a ventilator before ever we came to Stoke
                Moran.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">My dear <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>!</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Oh, yes, I did. You remember in her statement she said that her sister could smell
                <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char>'s cigar. Now, of course that suggested at once that there must be a
                communication between the two rooms. It could only be a small one, or it would have
                been remarked upon at the coroner's inquiry. I deduced a ventilator.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">But what harm can there be in that?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Well, there is at least a curious coincidence of dates. A ventilator is made, a
                cord is hung, and a lady who sleeps in the bed dies. Does not that strike
                you?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">I cannot as yet see any connection.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Did you observe anything very peculiar about that bed?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">No.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It was clamped to the floor. Did you ever see a bed fastened like that
                before?</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">I cannot say that I have.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The lady could not move her bed. It must always be in the same relative position
                to the ventilator and to the rope—or so we may call it, since it was clearly never
                meant for a bell-pull.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">Holmes,</quote> I cried, <quote speaker="johnWatson">I seem to see dimly what you are hinting at. We
                are only just in time to prevent some subtle and horrible crime.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Subtle enough and horrible enough. When a doctor does go wrong he is the first of
                criminals. He has nerve and he has knowledge. Palmer and Pritchard were among the
                heads of their profession. This man strikes even deeper, but I think,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>, that
                we shall be able to strike deeper still. But we shall have horrors enough before the
                night is over; for goodness' sake let us have a quiet pipe and turn our minds for a
                few hours to something more cheerful.</quote></p>

        <p>About nine o'clock the light among the trees was extinguished, and all was dark in the
            direction of the Manor House. Two hours passed slowly away, and then, suddenly, just at
            the stroke of eleven, a single bright light shone out right in front of us.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">That is our signal,</quote> said <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>, springing to his feet</action>; <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">it comes
                from the middle window.</quote></p>

        <p>As we passed out he exchanged a few words with the landlord, explaining that we were
            going on a late visit to an acquaintance, and that it was possible that we might spend
            the night there. A moment later we were out on the dark road, a chill wind blowing in
            our faces, and one yellow light twinkling in front of us through the gloom to guide us
            on our sombre errand.</p>

        <p>There was little difficulty in entering the grounds, for unrepaired breaches gaped in the
            old park wall. Making our way among the trees, we reached the lawn, crossed it, and were
            about to enter through the window when out from a clump of laurel bushes there darted
            what seemed to be a hideous and distorted child, who threw itself upon the grass with
            writhing limbs and then ran swiftly across the lawn into the darkness.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">My God!</quote> I whispered; <quote speaker="johnWatson">did you see it?</quote></p>

        <p><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> was for the moment as startled as I. His hand closed like a vice upon my wrist in
            his agitation. Then <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> broke into a low laugh and put his lips to my ear</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is a nice household,</quote> he murmured. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">That is the
            baboon.</quote></p>

        <p>I had forgotten the strange pets which the<char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott"> Doctor</char> affected. There was a cheetah, too;
            perhaps we might find it upon our shoulders at any moment. I confess that I felt easier
            in my mind when, after following <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>' example and slipping off my shoes, I found
            myself inside the bedroom. My companion noiselessly closed the shutters, moved the lamp
            onto the table, and cast his eyes round the room. All was as we had seen it in the
            daytime. <action>Then creeping up to me and making a trumpet of his hand, <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> whispered into my
            ear again so gently</action> that it was all that I could do to distinguish the words:</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The least sound would be fatal to our plans.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> nodded to show that I had heard.</action></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">We must sit without light. He would see it through the ventilator.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> nodded again</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">Do not go asleep; your very life may depend upon it. Have your pistol ready in
                case we should need it. I will sit on the side of the bed, and you in that
                chair.</quote></p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> took out my revolver and laid it on the corner of the table</action>.</p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">Holmes</char> had brought up a long thin cane, and this he placed upon the bed beside him. By it
            he laid the box of matches and the stump of a candle. Then he turned down the lamp, and
            we were left in darkness.</action></p>

        <p>How shall I ever forget that dreadful vigil? I could not hear a sound, not even the
            drawing of a breath, and yet I knew that my companion sat open-eyed, within a few feet
            of me, in the same state of nervous tension in which I was myself. The shutters cut off
            the least ray of light, and we waited in absolute darkness.</p>

        <p>From outside came the occasional cry of a night-bird, and once at our very window a long
            drawn catlike whine, which told us that the cheetah was indeed at liberty. Far away we
            could hear the deep tones of the parish clock, which boomed out every quarter of an
            hour. How long they seemed, those quarters! Twelve struck, and one and two and three,
            and still we sat waiting silently for whatever might befall.</p>

        <p>Suddenly there was the momentary gleam of a light up in the direction of the ventilator,
            which vanished immediately, but was succeeded by a strong smell of burning oil and
            heated metal. Someone in the next room had lit a dark-lantern. <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> heard a gentle sound of
            movement</action>, and then all was silent once more, though the smell grew stronger. For half an
            hour <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> sat with straining ears</action>. Then suddenly another sound became audible—a very
            gentle, soothing sound, like that of a small jet of steam escaping continually from a
            kettle. The instant that we heard it,<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>sprang from the bed, struck a match, and
            lashed furiously with his cane at the bell-pull</action>.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You see it,<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>?</quote> he yelled. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">You see it?</quote></p>

        <p>But I saw nothing. At the moment when<action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>struck the light</action> <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> heard a low, clear
            whistle</action>, but the sudden glare flashing into my weary eyes made it impossible for me to
            tell what it was at which my friend lashed so savagely. I could, however, see that his
            face was deadly pale and filled with horror and loathing. He had ceased to strike and
            was gazing up at the ventilator when suddenly there broke from the silence of the night
            the most horrible cry to which I have ever listened. It swelled up louder and louder, a
            hoarse yell of pain and fear and anger all mingled in the one dreadful shriek. They say
            that away down in the village, and even in the distant parsonage, that cry raised the
            sleepers from their beds. It struck cold to our hearts, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> stood gazing at Holmes</action>,
            and he at me, until the last echoes of it had died away into the silence from which it
            rose.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">What can it mean?</quote> I gasped.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It means that it is all over,</quote><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>answered. <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And perhaps, after
                all, it is for the best. Take your pistol, and we will enter <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Dr. Roylott</char>'s
                room.</quote></p>

        <p><action>With a grave face <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> lit the lamp and led the way down the corridor. Twice he struck at
            the chamber door without any reply from within. Then he turned the handle and entered</action>, <action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char>
            at his heels, with the cocked pistol in my hand</action>.</p>

        <p>It was a singular sight which met our eyes. On the table stood a dark-lantern with the
            shutter half open, throwing a brilliant beam of light upon the iron safe, the door of
            which was ajar. Beside this table, on the wooden chair, sat Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char> clad in
            a long grey dressing-gown, his bare ankles protruding beneath, and his feet thrust into
            red heelless Turkish slippers. Across his lap lay the short stock with the long lash
            which we had noticed during the day. <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">His</char> chin was cocked upward and his eyes were fixed
            in a dreadful, rigid stare at the corner of the ceiling. Round his brow he had a
            peculiar yellow band, with brownish speckles, which seemed to be bound tightly round his
            head</action>. As we entered he made neither sound nor motion.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">The band! the speckled band!</quote> whispered <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>.</p>

        <p><action><char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson">I</char> took a step forward</action>. In an instant his strange headgear began to move, and there reared
            itself from among his hair the squat diamond-shaped head and puffed neck of a loathsome
            serpent.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">It is a swamp adder!</quote> cried <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>; <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">the deadliest snake in India. He
                has died within ten seconds of being bitten. Violence does, in truth, recoil upon
                the violent, and the schemer falls into the pit which he digs for another. Let us
                thrust this creature back into its den, and we can then remove<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> to some
                place of shelter and let the county police know what has happened.</quote></p>

        <p><action>As <char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">he</char> spoke he drew the dog-whip swiftly from the dead man's lap, and throwing the noose
            round the reptile's neck he drew it from its horrid perch and, carrying it at arm's
            length, threw it into the iron safe, which he closed upon it.</action></p>

        <p>Such are the true facts of the death of Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char>, of Stoke Moran. It is not
            necessary that I should prolong a narrative which has already run to too great a length
            by telling how we broke the sad news to the terrified girl, how we conveyed her by the
            morning train to the care of her good aunt at Harrow, of how the slow process of
            official inquiry came to the conclusion that the doctor met his fate while indiscreetly
            playing with a dangerous pet. The little which I had yet to learn of the case was told
            me by Sherlock<char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes"> Holmes </char>as we travelled back next day.</p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I had,</quote> said he, <quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">come to an entirely erroneous conclusion which
                shows, my dear<char gender = "male" name = "johnWatson"> Watson</char>, how dangerous it always is to reason from insufficient data.
                The presence of the gipsies, and the use of the word 'band,' which was used by the
                poor girl, no doubt, to explain the appearance which she had caught a hurried
                glimpse of by the light of her match, were sufficient to put me upon an entirely
                wrong scent. I can only claim the merit that I instantly reconsidered my position
                when, however, it became clear to me that whatever danger threatened an occupant of
                the room could not come either from the window or the door. My attention was
                speedily drawn, as I have already remarked to you, to this ventilator, and to the
                bell-rope which hung down to the bed. The discovery that this was a dummy, and that
                the bed was clamped to the floor, instantly gave rise to the suspicion that the rope
                was there as a bridge for something passing through the hole and coming to the bed.
                The idea of a snake instantly occurred to me, and when I coupled it with my
                knowledge that the doctor was furnished with a supply of creatures from India, I
                felt that I was probably on the right track. The idea of using a form of poison
                which could not possibly be discovered by any chemical test was just such a one as
                would occur to a clever and ruthless man who had had an Eastern training. The
                rapidity with which such a poison would take effect would also, from his point of
                view, be an advantage. It would be a sharp-eyed coroner, indeed, who could
                distinguish the two little dark punctures which would show where the poison fangs
                had done their work. Then I thought of the whistle. Of course he must recall the
                snake before the morning light revealed it to the victim. He had trained it,
                probably by the use of the milk which we saw, to return to him when summoned. He
                would put it through this ventilator at the hour that he thought best, with the
                certainty that it would crawl down the rope and land on the bed. It might or might
                not bite the occupant, perhaps she might escape every night for a week, but sooner
                or later she must fall a victim.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">I had come to these conclusions before ever I had entered his room. An inspection
                of his chair showed me that he had been in the habit of standing on it, which of
                course would be necessary in order that he should reach the ventilator. The sight of
                the safe, the saucer of milk, and the loop of whipcord were enough to finally dispel
                any doubts which may have remained. The metallic clang heard by<char gender = "female" name = "helenStoner"> Miss Stoner</char> was
            obviously caused by <action><char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">her stepfather</char> hastily closing the door of his safe upon its
                terrible occupant.</action> Having once made up my mind, you know the steps which I took in
                order to put the matter to the proof. I heard the creature hiss as I have no doubt
                that you did also, and <action><char gender = "male" name = "sherlockHolmes">I</char> instantly lit the light and attacked it</action>.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="johnWatson">With the result of driving it through the ventilator.</quote></p>

        <p><quote speaker="sherlockHolmes">And also with the result of causing it to turn upon its master at the other side.
                Some of the blows of my cane came home and roused its snakish temper, so that it
                flew upon the first person it saw. In this way I am no doubt indirectly responsible
                for Dr. <char gender = "male" name = "grimesbyRoylott">Grimesby Roylott</char>'s death, and I cannot say that it is likely to weigh very
                heavily upon my conscience.</quote></p>


    </story>

</passage>
